<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>82MHz&#39; Blog</title>
    <link>https://82mhz.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 82MHz&#39; Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 13:50:48 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://82mhz.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.github.io/posts/oldcomputerchallenge_day3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 13:50:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.github.io/posts/oldcomputerchallenge_day3/</guid>
      <description>On this day I was sick, so not a lot has happened, but I would like to still briefly share a few thoughts.
I&amp;rsquo;m spending far less time aimlessly surfing the web or watching youtube-videos for hours on end, simply because it&amp;rsquo;s not very much fun. Surfing works, but most sites are not very pleasant to look at or don&amp;rsquo;t work at all in a minimalist browser (think lynx, links2, luakit) or they slow the computer down to a crawl when using vivaldi (which is already slow thanks to its significant memory footprint).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>82MHz</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 11:34:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Homepage of AK, I go by 82MHz online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.github.io/posts/oldcomputerchallenge_day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 18:00:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.github.io/posts/oldcomputerchallenge_day2/</guid>
      <description>Day 2 is coming to a close. Today I was at work all day and so didn&amp;rsquo;t spend a whole lot of time on my slow computer.
However, A thought occurred to me recently, because since I subscribed to mastodon a couple of weeks ago and especially since I started following some retro computing related postings (where I discoved the OCC in the first place), I discovered that there&amp;rsquo;s a thing called</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.github.io/posts/oldcomputerchallenge_day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 09:46:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.github.io/posts/oldcomputerchallenge_day1/</guid>
      <description>Okay, Day 1 is almost over, what have we learned?
Modern software sucks!!
I mean, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really, a lot of it is quite beautiful and easy to use, but boy, everything consumes so many resources! Just starting up a web browser (firefox or chrome doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter) takes a good ten seconds or more, and then we haven&amp;rsquo;t even loaded a single page yet.
And webpages are also so slow and bloated these days!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Preparation</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.github.io/posts/oldcomputerchallenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 09:46:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.github.io/posts/oldcomputerchallenge/</guid>
      <description>This year I learned about Solene&amp;rsquo;s Old Computer Challenge, and I thought hey, I might give it a go!
So this year the rules for the challenge are as follows:
Let&amp;rsquo;s use a SLOW computer for 7 days. This will be achieved by various means with any hardware:
Limit your computer&amp;rsquo;s CPU to use only 1 core. This can be set in the BIOS most of the time, and on Linux you can use maxcores=1 in the boot command line, on OpenBSD you can use bsd.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
