<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reading on 82MHz</title>
    <link>https://82mhz.net/tags/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reading on 82MHz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://82mhz.net/tags/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cal Newport&#39;s &#34;Deep Life Stack&#34; - Layer 1: Discipline</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/cal-newports-deep-life-stack-layer-1-discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/cal-newports-deep-life-stack-layer-1-discipline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last post I introduced Cal Newport&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Deep Life Stack&amp;rdquo;, his program to put your life on a more solid foundation. Today I want to expand on this and have a look at the fist layer, &amp;ldquo;discipline&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we want to start some meaningful changes in our lives, the first step, according to Cal, is to change our peception of ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our thinking and our behaviour are deeply linked together. If I am well organised, have everything under control and can stay calm even when faced with difficult situations, I also have the mental image of being well organised with a decent amount of self-discipline. But if I have been living my life without much of a plan and maybe have a few &amp;ldquo;skeletons in the closet&amp;rdquo;, like unfinished projects, or 20 failed attempts at dieting, or attempting to overhaul my life again and again without success, then the mental image I have of myself is probably not the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s where the discipline layer can help. If (I&amp;rsquo;m exaggerating here) I think of myself as a loser who can&amp;rsquo;t get anything done anyway because that&amp;rsquo;s the way it has always been (doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if this is actually the case or if this is only in my mind), then it will be almost impossible for me to change because my attitude will be &amp;ldquo;I will fail anyway&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So first we have to change our image of ourselves. And since we can not really change our thoughts, the way to get there is to change our behaviour first, and the thoughts and our self-perception will follow. This is classic behavioural psychology and the same basic idea behavioural therapy is based on. Body and mind are one and influence each other, changes in behaviour are followed by changes in the mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what do we do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cal suggests creating three keystone habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exact nature of these three habits is less important, the goal is to convince yourself that you are able to set your mind on something and then follow through, even if it is not always easy or pleasant. In other words, you should start thinking of yourself as a disciplined person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The habits should therefore require a certain investment of time and energy, but they should still be managebale on a daily basis. If you want to improve your fitness, &amp;ldquo;I look at my dumbbells once a day&amp;rdquo; is probaly not enough, as it will hardly have any impact, but &amp;ldquo;I do a hardcore 90 minutes Crossfit workout every day&amp;rdquo; is way too much, you will not be able to keep this up for long. It should be something in between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, the habits are spread across different areas of your life, for example one habit could be about health/spirituality, one about work/profession and one about your hobbies/personal development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After thinking about this for a while (in other words, totally overthinking it), I&amp;rsquo;ve settled on these three keystone habits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing&lt;/strong&gt;: I want to spend at least 15 minutes every day writing something. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what or how, it can be on a computer, can be on paper, can be a journal entry, a blog article, a short story&amp;hellip; whatever. Just write.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yoga/Meditation&lt;/strong&gt;: I want to spend 20 minutes every day practicing meditation or doing a small yoga session, therefore doing something for my mental and physical health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cleaning my apartment&lt;/strong&gt;: I will set aside some time each day (doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how much or how little) to clean and tidy up my place, because my surroundings have a huge impact on how I&amp;rsquo;m feeling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to to track these habits, I just downloaded a habit tracker template from some random website and printed it out so that I can record and check off every day that I have my habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now let&amp;rsquo;s do this for a few weeks, and then we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the next layer, where we&amp;rsquo;ll look at our values and bring them up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post 005/100 of the 100DaysToOffload Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a translation of the original German post made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; and then manually adapted to (hopefully) sound a bit more human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cal Newport&#39;s &#34; Deep Life Stack&#34;: 4 Months to reinvent your life </title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/cal-newports-deep-life-stack-4-months-to-reinvent-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/cal-newports-deep-life-stack-4-months-to-reinvent-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I usually stay away from the &amp;ldquo;productivity&amp;rdquo; genre on YouTube as far as possible, because there are just too many influencers on there who boast about how great they are at being productive, how super sophisticated their productivity system or bullet journal is, or who produce these quite frankly ridiculous &amp;ldquo;study with me for 13 hours&amp;rdquo; videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very pleasant exception to this is Cal Newport&amp;rsquo;s podcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calnewport.com/&#34;&gt;Cal Newport&lt;/a&gt; has been blogging about productivity since around 2007, has by now published 7 books (including &amp;ldquo;Deep Work&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Digital Minimalism&amp;rdquo;), has been running a weekly podcast for a few years now (early on he posted several times a week) and regularly publishes long form articles in magazines such as &amp;ldquo;The New Yorker&amp;rdquo;. And these are all just things he does on the side; his day job is being a professor of computer science at Georgetown University in Washington DC. So I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s wrong to assume he knows a thing or two about productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and he&amp;rsquo;s also my exact age, which may or may not trigger a bit of anxiety and feeling of inadequacy in me&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, his approach is not &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to get a new bullet journal&amp;rdquo;, but more general and holistic, he&amp;rsquo;s all about how to set up your life in such a way that you get the things you want to do done and still have free time and energy left so you&amp;rsquo;re not constantly stressed out of your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I like a lot about his podcast is that he often presents ideas that are still in the making and then picks them up again in later episodes and develops them further. In one of his latest &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0G7Wu4DnDaw&#34;&gt;podcast episodes&lt;/a&gt; he presented a 4-month plan to put your life on a new, hopefully more stable ground. This is based on an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G-6ua6UCeGM&#34;&gt;earlier idea&lt;/a&gt; that he continues to develop and refine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He suggests to divide the procedure into four successive layers which he calls the &amp;ldquo;deep life stack&amp;rdquo;. Here it is as a picture, with an explanation afterwards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;https://82mhz.net/images/CalNewport4MonthsEN.svg&#34; height=&#34;400x&#34; alt=&#34;4 layers, discipline, values, control, vision&#34;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four layers that build on each other are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discipline as the lowest layer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Values as the second&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control as the third&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vision as the highest and last&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give just a very rough summary, the individual layers are about the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discipline: Develop an image of yourself as a disciplined person&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Values: Reflect on and clearly define your own values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control: Take control over recurring tasks, automate or eliminate where possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vision: Develop a plan for how yout life should develop in the next X months/years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to discuss the individual levels, how Cal defines them and my thoughts on them in more detail in later posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach makes a lot of sense to me, and since I am currently thinking a lot about where I want my life to be headed, I think this a good way for me to deal with it in a more structured manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cal suggests to set apart two weeks for the first layer (discipline), 4 weeks for the next two and 6 weeks for the last (vision). That makes the whole process last about four months. He recommends starting at the beginning of September, because then you end up exactly at the end of December after four months and start the new year with a structured plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m starting this week, in mid-September instead of early September, but that&amp;rsquo;s okay. I&amp;rsquo;m off work for three weeks now and so I have enough time to start thinking about this, and also my birthday is coming up, which is generally a good time to reflect on my life and plan where to go next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post 004/100 of the 100DaysToOffload Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a translation of the original German post made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; and then manually adapted to (hopefully) sound a bit more human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books I read in August 2023</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/books-i-read-in-august-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/books-i-read-in-august-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first post of what I hope will be a monthly series in which I take a look back at the books I read the past month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really reach my goal of one book a week, which was partly due to the fact that I started some books and put them down again after two or three days, because I realised that they just weren&amp;rsquo;t right for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I managed to read three books, which I want to briefly summarise here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;atwood&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Margaret Atwood&lt;/em&gt;: The Handmaids Tale&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw this book somewhere online on a list of the best sci-fi novels of the 80s when I was looking for new reading material, and since the title looked vaguely familiar (there is an adaptation of the material as a TV series, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen it), I decided to give it a read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily call the book science fiction though, it&amp;rsquo;s more of an alternate reality, what-if scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, what if the radical evangelical Christians rose to power in the US and turned the country into a theocracy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outcome is pretty much what you&amp;rsquo;d expect: A Christian version of the current Islamic theocracies, coupled with the cold inhumane atmosphere of Catholic schools and orphanages of (hopefully) days gone by, and with a bit of Nazi Germany sprinkled on top. Women have no rights, have to be subservient to men at all times and are pretty much only there to have children (if they can, because many people became sterile in the preceding war, especially the men). The men are in charge, and anyone who is even remotely suspected of not being completely in line with the ideology is hanged or shot on sight. Love thy neighbour, you know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main character is the maid Offred, who is one of the few remaining fertile women and therefore lives in the house of the Commander and his wife Serena Joy, where she is subjected once a month to a bizarre impregnation ritual by the Commander and his wife and treated like dirt the rest of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book starts on a random day in Offred&amp;rsquo;s life with Offred just talking about her everyday life, and so a picture of the world she lives in, how it came about, and what kind of life she had before only emerges very slowly. This makes it a bit hard at first to get into the story, but once you&amp;rsquo;re in, you can&amp;rsquo;t put the book down and just shiver again and again at how strange and insane and yet absolutely within the realm of possibility the world described here is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;woz&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steve Wozniak&lt;/em&gt;: iWoz&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this book, I had the weird feeling that I might have read it before, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really remember much, so I just read it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Wozniak is the co-founder of Apple (together with the other, more famous Steve) and the one who designed the first Apple computers completely by himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this autobiography he goes over his life, from his childhood, where his father, also an engineer, introduced him to the world of electronics, to his first computer designs, to his first real job at HP, his first encounter with Steve Jobs, the founding of Apple Computers and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely exciting to read and you get a good look into the history of the micro computer from a very unique perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But. The book reads as if he just spent a few hours recording everything he could think of into a voice recording app and then someone typed it all up, put it in the right order and called it a book. His style of speaking is very redundant and verbose (not to say rambling), and a little more care in editing to make it more concise and to the point would have helped the reading flow a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;goldberg&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Natalie Goldberg&lt;/em&gt;: Writing down the Bones&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If The Internet&lt;sup&gt;TM&lt;/sup&gt; is to be believed, &amp;ldquo;Writing down the Bones&amp;rdquo; or as it is called in German &amp;ldquo;writing in cafés&amp;rdquo; (why translate a title when you can just make up a completely different one?) is one of THE books about creative writing, and what better reading is there at the beginning of a blogging challenge than such a book?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I went for it and was not disappointed! The book is divided into many small, unconnected chapters, each of which is self-contained and they cover a range of topics, from philosophical reflections about writing to concrete tips or simply observations of the author about herself and her relationship to writing. So you can just pick it up again and again and look through it and read a chapter or two for inspiration, whatever you feel like in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highly recommended, The Internet didn&amp;rsquo;t promise too much! I think if I come across a cheap copy of the book (I borrowed it from the library), I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely get it just to have it on the table and flip through it every now and then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post 003/100 of the 100DaysToOffload Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a translation of the original German post made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; and then manually adapted to (hopefully) sound a bit more human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogroll or &#34;I want one too!&#34;</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/blogroll-or-i-want-one-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/blogroll-or-i-want-one-too/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by Noisy Deadline&amp;rsquo;s post &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://noisydeadlines.net/blog-update-bringing-back-the-blogroll&#34;&gt;Bringing back the Blogroll&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; and by the blogrolls I&amp;rsquo;ve already seen on some other sites, I wanted to set one up for myself too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the concept of a blogroll, which as far as I understand is a list of blogs I like and follow (which I already have on my links page), but I thought I could do one better and create a list of all the latest posts from these blogs as well, ordered by date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first saw this concept on &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.mozz.us/gopher/i-logout.cz/1/bongusta&#34;&gt;Bongusta!&lt;/a&gt;, which is a gopher phlog aggregator, and matto has the same thing on his &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.mozz.us/gopher/box.matto.nl/1/phlogroll&#34;&gt;gophersite&lt;/a&gt; as well, so I stole the idea from them (without feeling even a trace of guilt or remorse!) and created my own version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some failed attempts, I decided to use the tool &lt;strong&gt;sfeed&lt;/strong&gt;, which fetches the latest posts from a list of rss feeds and writes them to a tab-delimited text file for each feed. There is also an option to output the list of new posts directly as html, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like the formatting, I really wanted to sort according to the latest posts of all feeds sorted by date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I built my own parser in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this sounds like &amp;ldquo;just quickly whipped something up&amp;rdquo;, but since I&amp;rsquo;m not a Python expert and had to google every single command, it took me a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now it works, sfeed fetches the latest articles from a list of RSS feeds, my Python script parses them out as Markdown in the right format and Hugo then integrates it into the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result can be admired &lt;a href=&#34;../../../../blogroll&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and can be accessed via the menu option &amp;ldquo;links&amp;rdquo;. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll add a separate menu entry, I&amp;rsquo;m not quite sure yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, I&amp;rsquo;m happy with it for now. So far I&amp;rsquo;m still updating manually, so the list might be a few days behind. If I find the time and feel like it, I&amp;rsquo;ll switch to automated updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post 002/100 of the 100DaysToOffload-Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a translation of the original German post made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; and then manually adapted to (hopefully) sound a bit more human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Days to offload</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/100-days-to-offload/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/100-days-to-offload/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes there are things that you read or just see somewhere and you immediately think &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rsquo;s cool, I&amp;rsquo;ll do that&amp;rdquo;. Some time ago I came across the &lt;a href=&#34;https://100daystooffload.com/&#34;&gt;100 Days to offload&lt;/a&gt; challenge, and this was one of those things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge is to write 100 blogposts within one year. Of course, I mentioned it right away on Mastodon that I was doing the challenge, so now I have the self-imposed task of writing 100 blogposts within one year, i.e. from today until the end of August 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are simple, to quote from the website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some simple and reasonable guidelines if you want to take part in #100DaysToOffload:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This needs to be done on a personal blog, not a corporate blog. If you don’t have a personal blog, you can sign up for a free one at &lt;a href=&#34;https://bearblog.dev&#34;&gt;Bear Blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no specific start date. Your 100 posts can start or end whenever you want them to, they just need to be completed within 365 days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish 100 new posts in the space of a year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are no limits to what you can post about – write about whatever interests you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you have published an article, don’t forget to post a link on your social media with the hashtag &lt;code&gt;#100DaysToOffload&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get your friends involved!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What topics should I write about? No idea! Whatever comes to mind, probably a lot of stuff about tech, tutorials, some hobby projects I&amp;rsquo;m doing, rants about cars and lousy city design&amp;hellip; I think there are enough things to get off my chest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I posted on Mastodon that I&amp;rsquo;m doing the challenge and was looking for fellow participants, a few people actually came forward, so here are some of my fellow participants in random order &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dustin also wants to start today (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.spotek.io/@dustin&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://0xdstn.site/&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screwtape as well (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.sdf.org/@screwtape&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gopher.tildeverse.org/tilde.club/1/~screwtape/synthember-100days-tooffload/&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matto (&lt;a href=&#34;https://pub.matto.nl/u/matto&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://box.matto.nl/&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.mozz.us/gopher/box.matto.nl/&#34;&gt;Phlog&lt;/a&gt;) and Prahou (&lt;a href=&#34;https://merveilles.town/@prahou&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://triapul.cz/&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.mozz.us/gopher/triapul.cz/&#34;&gt;Phlog&lt;/a&gt;) have already started last month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And Noisy Deadlines (&lt;a href=&#34;https://writing.exchange/@noisydeadlines&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://noisydeadlines.net/&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;) thought, one year is way too long, I can do it in 1/3 of the time!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might now be wondering, what the &amp;hellip; is a phlog?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, some people have normal http websites, but there are also the purists who use text-based protocols, either &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gopher&#34;&gt;Gopher&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gemini_(protocol)&#34;&gt;Gemini&lt;/a&gt;, and depending on the protocol, the pages are then called blogs (http), phlogs (gopher) or gemlogs (gemini). What do you know! I had no idea&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll limit myself to this website here for now, but maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll add a gopher or gemini site in the future, we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now to complete the confusion about all the outdated retro protocols:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matto has set up a channel on IRC at &lt;a href=&#34;ircs://irc.libera.chat:6697&#34;&gt;libera.chat&lt;/a&gt; called #phloggersgarage, where a nice little community around blogging (phlogging&amp;hellip;) is already slowly developing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s going to be exciting, interesting, challenging and I&amp;rsquo;m sure also frustrating at times over the next few months, but that&amp;rsquo;s all part of a challenge, otherwise it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a translation of the original German post made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; and then manually adapted to (hopefully) sound a bit more human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I post the gopher pages here via http proxy. I hope the purists will forgive me, but this is the way I access the pages so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to leave the comfort of my web browser&amp;hellip;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Design Part 2</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/08/updated-design-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/08/updated-design-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know it: You only want to change a minor thing on the theme of the website, but you can&amp;rsquo;t seem to get it right and in the end escalate completely and rewrite the whole website from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;back-story&#34;&gt;Back story:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website was created with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and originally had the theme &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/themes/hugo-papermod/&#34;&gt;Papermod&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, then &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/themes/hugo-blog-awesome/&#34;&gt;Hugo Blog Awesome&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; and finally &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/themes/hugo-theme-console/&#34;&gt;Console&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really happy with any of these themes, so I had already modified the Console theme quite a bit to be more like what I wanted it to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, some things in the CSS were quite weirdly implemented, and no matter what I tried, some things just didn&amp;rsquo;t work out the way I wanted them to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;and-now&#34;&gt;And now:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometime during the past week I had enough and just started to rewrite the whole site from scratch. The structure of course stays as it was before, but without all the things in the code I don&amp;rsquo;t need anyway and with a CSS that does exactly what (and only what!) I want. And with a little help from a good friend, who happens to be a web designer, I think I did a pretty good job!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things are still a bit rough and in need of improvement of course, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure there will be the occasional change here and there, but I think for now I have the site the way I like it and the way I imagined it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now the blogging can really start. More about that at the end of next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and a big sorry to those who have subscribed to my RSS feed, I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I&amp;rsquo;ve caused a bit of a mess there. I hope the time of big changes is over now and the site can stay the way it is for some time to come!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a translation of the original German post made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; and then manually adapted to (hopefully) sound a bit more human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website update with new sections</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/08/website-update-with-new-sections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/08/website-update-with-new-sections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a little announcement today, I have added two new sections to the website: Links and Bookclub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links should be pretty self-explanatory, on this page I collect links to interesting blogs, articles, documents&amp;hellip;. everything I find interesting or worth knowing and want to share or remember for later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under bookclub I collect the list of books I&amp;rsquo;ve read, maybe a book review here and there and generally everything that somehow has to do with books and reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mainly read either SciFi or non-fiction about psychology, society, technology and everything in between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggestions and recommendations for good books that don&amp;rsquo;t yet appear here are always welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Design and now also in German</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/08/new-design-and-now-also-in-german/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/08/new-design-and-now-also-in-german/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The site is barely two months old and already the first redesign is coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t really warm up to the old theme, but luckily Hugo makes it really easy to change the theme. Of course, you&amp;rsquo;re still going to spend days tinkering to get everything exactly the way you want it, and it&amp;rsquo;s still not exactly the way &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; want it, but that will come in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the site is now based on a modified &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrmierzejewski/hugo-theme-console&#34;&gt;Hugo Console Theme&lt;/a&gt; and, big news, it&amp;rsquo;s bilingual!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo makes it incredibly easy to create a bilingual site and switch back and forth between languages. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t a thing I was even considering when I decided to use Hugo, but it&amp;rsquo;s a happy coincidence now after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan is to write the posts in German, because I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt a bit weird writing everything in English (a foreign language for me) and then translating the German posts into English with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe go over it again so that it sounds like me and not like an AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see how I get on with it. I won&amp;rsquo;t translate the older posts into German for now, but I think we can live with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a translation of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://82mhz.net/de/posts/redesign&#34;&gt;original German post&lt;/a&gt; made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; and then manually adapted to (hopefully) sound a bit more human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge 2023 - Epilogue</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/08/old-computer-challenge-2023-epilogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/08/old-computer-challenge-2023-epilogue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So the OCC 2023 ended almost three weeks ago and everyone went back to the year 2023 and to using their modern computers. At least I did. But let&amp;rsquo;s explore what remaind for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to take a moment to look back and examine what was good, which tools and workflows stuck with me and what is better left back on the old computer (which was really just a VM in my case).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-good&#34;&gt;The Good&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On both my Desktop and Laptop Computers I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href=&#34;https://endeavouros.com&#34;&gt;Endeavouros&lt;/a&gt;, which is pretty much a preconfigured and nice looking Arch Linux with a few extras here and there. And because I am already familiar with it, I decided to just use this as the basis for my OCC computer as well, though with a much slimmer graphical interface (no KDE, just a &lt;a href=&#34;https://herbstluftwm.org/&#34;&gt;minimal tiling window manager&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main things I do on my private computer on a daily basis are communicating with friends, browse the web, watch videos on Youtube, listen to music, do some occasional coding and try my best not to spend too much time on social media (these days mostly Mastodon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lived (out of necessity of course) much more in the terminal than I usually do. I still, unfortunately communicate with friends and family via WhatsApp a lot, which I normally have open in a browser window because I hate typing on a touchscreen (if any manufacturer wants to bring back haptic keys with T9 support, I&amp;rsquo;m ready!). Like pretty much everything related to the modern web, this was more an exercise in frustration than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since just opening a browser window filled up about half my RAM before I even opened a single website, having a bunch of tabs open at all times and flipping between them quickly turned out to be impossible. So I needed to find ways to use WhatsApp, IRC, Mastodon, Youtube, VS Code, Obsidian and a few other programs and services on a computer with limited resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;rsquo;s a surprising number of very lightweight terminal apps around for pretty much every usecase, I was surprised!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ones that stuck with me were&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/d99kris/nchat&#34;&gt;nchat&lt;/a&gt; for Whatsapp, which has a very nice ncurses interface and works beautifully (remember to install the font &lt;a href=&#34;https://fonts.google.com/noto/specimen/Noto+Emoji&#34;&gt;noto-fonts-emoji&lt;/a&gt; if you want to see emojis instead of unicode placeholders)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/RasmusLindroth/tut&#34;&gt;tut&lt;/a&gt; for Mastodon, same thing, beautiful ncurses interface, works like a charm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lynx.invisible-island.net&#34;&gt;lynx&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://links.twibright.com&#34;&gt;links2&lt;/a&gt; for web browsing in the terminal (no problem on lightweight static websites, but horrible for modern webapps bloated with js etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://irssi.org&#34;&gt;irssi&lt;/a&gt; for IRC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rawtext.club/~sloum/bombadillo.html&#34;&gt;bombadillo&lt;/a&gt; for accessing gemini and gopher sites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And for coding, writing blog entries etc. I just used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vim.org/&#34;&gt;best terminal editor&lt;/a&gt; ever (once you learn how to use it, that is!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially I considered watching Youtube just impossible, but a few days into the OCC someone pointed me to &lt;a href=&#34;https://yewtu.be&#34;&gt;https://yewtu.be&lt;/a&gt;, where I could search for a video, get the URL, copy it to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yt-dlp/yt-dlp&#34;&gt;yt-dlp&lt;/a&gt; and just download the video in a resolution low enough to be watchable on my system. Neat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For listening to music I used my old iPod or just turned the radio on (yes, FM radio still exists! I was surprised, too).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of these apps I actually still keep using, like nchat, tut, bombadillo and irssi, because they&amp;rsquo;re just so lightweight and easily started with a few keystrokes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to say though, the most difficult thing about learning all these terminal apps was to memorize all the different key combinations! What&amp;rsquo;s just a click on the right button in a GUI turns into hunting around for which key combination does what you want to do, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that every single piece of software seems to invent its own shortcuts! Want to look at an attached media file? in tut it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;rsquo;m&amp;rsquo;, but in nchat it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;ctrl+v&amp;rsquo;. And it&amp;rsquo;s like that for everything&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s maddening! Once you&amp;rsquo;ve gotten used to it though, everything flies and is much simpler to use than clicking around in bloated graphical UIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So everything is great, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-bad&#34;&gt;The Bad&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short: The web. Just everything about it. I already mentioned that just firing up Firefox or Vivaldi (my browser of choice for most things) uses a good chunk of RAM, and opening pretty much any website quickly fills up the rest. My system was constantly swapping, which of course slows everything down even further, and I was really glad I had an SSD, otherwise I would have had to live with the sound of a constantly whirring mechanical harddrive in my ears while slowly going insane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using text based browsers is possible, but by far not all websites load or are usable, so you often have to switch to a gui based browser and suffer. And that&amp;rsquo;s with all adblockers turned to maximum and JS disabled where possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could write a whole article about this, and maybe one day I will, but the modern web is just becoming more and more awful to use with every passing year. We&amp;rsquo;re burning gigawatthours worth of energy and are producing tons and tons of CO2 in the process just to transmit ads and self playing videos and all kinds of other crap that &lt;strong&gt;nobody even wants&lt;/strong&gt; through the net! And for what? So big corporations can get richer and richer, while the rest of us are being stripped of our privacy and the global climate is going to hell along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s never been more apparent to me than in the last few weeks: The modern web (and by extension a lot of the rest of the modern world) is a mistake. We should just hit &lt;em&gt;reset&lt;/em&gt;, go back to 1995 or so and start over, and do it better. What we&amp;rsquo;re doing right now is clearly not sustainable, nor is it healthy (not for the environment and not for our minds).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I don&amp;rsquo;t want to end on this sour note, because there was also&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-great&#34;&gt;The Great&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community! Without a doubt, that was the best part of it! People were blogging about it, talking on Mastodon and IRC exchanging ideas and frustrations, giving each other support and tips&amp;hellip; it was great. &lt;strong&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong&gt; how being social online is supposed to work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So thank you Solene for coming up with the OCC, thank you to all the participants who shared their experiences and thank you to everyone who read my posts and helped me out where necessary!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to doing this again next year :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Days 6 and 7</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-days-6-and-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 07:29:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-days-6-and-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So the last two days of the Old Computer Challenge went by in the blink of an eye, and not a lot has happened, so I&amp;rsquo;m putting them together in one post. But I still wanted to note a few things down, and I might also a wrap-up some time next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;day-6&#34;&gt;Day 6&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was boiling hot outside (35°C) and I am just completely useless in these kinds of temperatures (in Germany we also don&amp;rsquo;t tend to have AC, so no way to cool my apartment down). So I was just lying around most of the day, trying to move as little as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in the evening it cooled down and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d explore the &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; site of the internet some more, this time in the form of looking at Bulletin Board Systems (BBS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now these are definitely a product and technology of the 80s, and I am too young to have experienced them in their time (in the 80s I was busy learning to walk, talk and digest solid food), so I don&amp;rsquo;t have any nostalgia for them, but some are still around and some are around again, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d have a look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first thought was, I want the authentic experience, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try it on real hardware! I still have my dads old C64 here, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have a modem for it, so that idea was scrapped immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, how about BMC64 on a Raspberry Pi? I tried it before and it felt like a pretty authentic C64 experience (esp. on a Raspi 400), but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have network drivers, so no luck there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C64 mini maybe? But again, it can&amp;rsquo;t access the net. Next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raspberry Pi with an emulator? I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like going thorugh the trouble of downloading an image and setting everything up, so nope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, Vice emulator on my PC. Here I cheated because I used my regular computer, not the slow one, because running emulation on it might have been too much to ask of it. But after downloading the emulator and googling around for a suitable terminal software I realized that the process of getting it running might be a bit more involved than I anticipated, and I really didn&amp;rsquo;t have the patience, so I abandoned that too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So eventually I settled on downloading syncterm, which can emulate all kinds of old terminals, including the C64s, and finally I could google the addresses of some BBSs and see what it was like back 40 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I realized pretty quickly that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t my cup of tea. While it was interesting to see how much love went into some of these boards, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t really get into them. Maybe on authentic hardware and an old CRT it will be a better experience, but looking at huge ugly fonts on a modern laptop display just didn&amp;rsquo;t feel good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BBC from The Old Net even has the capability to open modern websites on it, so I tried a few, but again, the font is huge and ugly and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy to read&amp;hellip; I think for me this is missing the nostalgia factor that makes the experience special. But without the rose-tinted glasses on it felt a bit too old-school for my taste. My nostalgia for C64 and Amiga lies in the games, and my experiences with the online world began towards the end of the 90s, so that&amp;rsquo;s what feels nostalgic for me and what I enjoy revisiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, it was an interesting experience and I learned something in the process, if only about myself ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;day-7&#34;&gt;Day 7&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this day is even shorter to wrap up, because I was at a family gathering all day and didn&amp;rsquo;t use my computer much at all. I only had my phone with my and did my best to stick to my rules of only using it for communication, but I may have accidentally opened the browser once or twice&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with that the Old Computer Challenge is coming to an end!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was fun, frustrating and enlightening at various times! The best thing was by far the community on the fediverse, IRC and reading all the blog entries and experiences of the other participants! I can&amp;rsquo;t wait what @solene has in store for us next year and I will definitely participate again and try to keep in touch with some of the people I met along the way. And for that alone the experience was worth it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will summarize my thoughts in a few days, so there will be one more post, but for now I&amp;rsquo;m relieved to have a computer that feels fast again to work with ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Day 5: Youtube Videos on an iPod Classic</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-5-youtube-videos-on-an-ipod-classic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 15:11:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-5-youtube-videos-on-an-ipod-classic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;note&#34;&gt;Note&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only semi-related to the OldComputerChallenge, but I revisited the idea of downloading videos from Youtube and putting them on an old iPod. I had already figured out the commands a while ago, but I had to refresh my memory from my bash history and because I figure this might actually be of interest to some people, I wrote it as a tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, this is about downloading videos from Youtube and putting them on the iPod, not about accessing Youtube straight from the iPod. That&amp;rsquo;s not possible because iPods (apart from the iPod touch, which is basically an iPhone) don&amp;rsquo;t have wifi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while ago I got into old iPods (of course like so many people thanks to a certain &lt;a href=&#34;https://yewtu.be/channel/UC7Jwj9fkrf1adN4fMmTkpug&#34;&gt;easily excitable australian youtuber&lt;/a&gt;) and got myself an old iPod Classic with a 160GB harddisk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember thinking back then that they looked really amazing and that 160GB was just a phenomenal amount of storage, enough for my entire music collection at the time, but of course being a university student who was just barely getting by financially there was no way I could afford one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a decade and a half later, thankfully I have an income now and old iPods have come down in price as well (double win!), so the time had come to get one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://82mhz.net/iPodClassic.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;iPodClassic&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course the first thing I did was to put &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rockbox.org&#34;&gt;Rockbox&lt;/a&gt; on it, and here it is running the fantastic &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/D0-0K/adwaitapod&#34;&gt;Adawaitapod&lt;/a&gt; theme by &lt;a href=&#34;https://d00k.net/&#34;&gt;D00k&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So then putting music and podcasts and audiobooks on it is pretty straightforward, just copy your MP3s, OGGs, FLACs etc. over and you&amp;rsquo;re good to go! No iTunes, no messing around trying to get libgtkpod working, it just works like any other MP3-Player, you mount it as a USB-storage device on your computer, copy the files over and that&amp;rsquo;s it. The way it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, this thing can play videos too, right? Could it be possible to rip videos from youtube and put them on the iPod so I can strain my eyes watching them on a way too tiny screen like it&amp;rsquo;s 2005?&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course it is, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have wasted your time with this introduction if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;necessary-software&#34;&gt;Necessary software&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need two pieces of software:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yt-dlp/yt-dlp&#34;&gt;yt-dlp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ffmpeg.org/&#34;&gt;ffmpeg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where to get them and how to install them depends on your OS and distro of choice of course, so I&amp;rsquo;m not going to write up a tutorial about that, I&amp;rsquo;m going to assume you can figure it out and have it installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ripping-the-videos-from-youtube-with-yt-dlp&#34;&gt;Ripping the video(s) from Youtube with yt-dlp&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, get the URL of the youtube-video you would like to rip. Just open the video in your browser and copy it from your browsers address bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, run yt-dlp with the URL as parameter, and I like to tell it to rip the 480p version of the video to save bandwidth. We need to make the video even smaller for the iPod, so there is no point in downloading the full 1080p or 4k file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ yt-dlp -S &amp;#34;res:480&amp;#34; &amp;#39;https://www.youtube.com/XXXXX&amp;#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note the quotation marks (&amp;rsquo;), they are necessary in case the youtube link contains characters that the shell would interpret as special characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works on playlists too btw! Just get the URL of the playlist instead and run yt-dlp like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ yt-dlp -S &amp;#34;res:480&amp;#34; --yes-playlist &amp;#39;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XXXXX&amp;#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now we will most likely end up with a video (or videos) in the &lt;em&gt;webm&lt;/em&gt; file format. That&amp;rsquo;s nice, but way too modern and high-res for our tiny little iPod. So let&amp;rsquo;s make it smaller and crappier!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;converting-for-the-ipod-with-ffmpeg&#34;&gt;Converting for the iPod with ffmpeg&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here we come across an unfortunate issue. The iPod is modern enough to be able to decode h.264 videos in hardware, but Rockbox has no support for it and can only decode the older (and worse) mpeg2 standard. What this means in practice is that we need to convert the videos to mpeg2 which creates bigger files than h.264 at a comparable quality or worse looking video at the same filesize. Quality is of less concern in my opinion, because the iPods screen is tiny and a few compression artefacts here and there only add to the retro experience, but filesize might be important if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of space available on the iPod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, we now need to fire up ffmpeg to convert the video to a format the iPod (and Rockbox) understands. The command is pretty straightforward, the for loop is only necessary if you have downloaded multiple videos, but it also works if you have only one video, so I only ever use this line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ for i in *.webm; do ffmpeg -i &amp;#34;$i&amp;#34; -c:v mpeg2video -b:v 4000k -acodec libmp3lame -ab 192k -vf scale=320:-1 &amp;#34;${i%.*}.mpg&amp;#34;; done
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to change the filesize (and quality), you can play around with the video bitrate (the number after -b:v) and the audio bitrate (the number after -ab) until you have the right values dialed in for your usecase. The bitrates above work well for me, so I&amp;rsquo;m happy with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if everything went well, you have a bunch of video files in your folder with the extension *&lt;em&gt;mpg&lt;/em&gt;, and you can just copy them over to your iPod, open them in Rockbox like any other file and enjoy your favorite 80s music videos on the go! (I know that&amp;rsquo;s what you came here for ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://82mhz.net/iPodClassicMJ.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;iPodClassic&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(It looks better in person btw., my camera is not the greatest. But the iPods screen is actually pretty nice for its age!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bonus-round-converting-to-h264-for-the-original-ipod-software&#34;&gt;Bonus round: Converting to h.264 for the original iPod software&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I mentioned, the iPod is capable of playing h.264 videos, so if you&amp;rsquo;re still rocking the original Apple software, you can also convert you videos to a higher quality (and smaller filesize) codec like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt; for i in *.webm; do ffmpeg -i &amp;#34;$i&amp;#34; -f mp4 -vcodec mpeg4 -vf scale=-2:320 -maxrate 1536k -b:v 768k -qmin 3 -qmax 5 -bufsize 4096k -g 300 -c:a aac -b:a 192k -ar 44100 -ac 2 &amp;#34;${i%.*}.mp4&amp;#34;; done
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPod Classic which I have came out in 2007 but the first iPod to allow video playback, the iPod Video, was released in 2005. They are technically very similar and have the same screen.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Day 4</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 08:50:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to take this post to get out some thoughts about the internet, social media and mental health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is this related to the OldComputerChallenge?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the longest time now I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a facebook profile, and I never had a twitter profile or a tiktok account or a profile on any of the new social media platforms that are en vogue these days. The only social media I had left was Instagram, but I stopped using it a few months ago because I realized I was just mindlessly scrolling through posts for hours on end without getting much value or enjoyment out of it at all. Which is exactly what the platform wants me to do of course, but it&amp;rsquo;s also the exact opposite of what &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; want to do. So I ditched it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I was better off for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But because I still keep an eye out on what&amp;rsquo;s new and exciting in internetland (Neuland, as our head of state famously called it a few years ago), I was intrigued by mastodon and the fediverse and the idea of having my own blog and not being at the mercy of an eccentric billionaire who could turn my profile off at any moment with no way for me to ever get it back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I got an account on mastodon. And started following a few people, and a few hashtags, and discovered the OldComputerChallenge. And that there was a whole community of people hosting their own blogs on simple webservers, using gopher or gemini, chatting on IRC and basically using the internet like it was 1999 (or so). So that intrigued me, and I decided to do the OldComputerChallenge as well, and blog about it and be in touch with the other participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then something interesting happened. The first few days I tried to keep up with all the blogs, keep up with IRC, follow all the retrocomputing-related tags on mastodon, write my own posts and do all that while working in a slow OS with unfamiliar tools and workflows&amp;hellip; and I got stressed. A lot. I tried to do too many things, keep up with too many posts, flip back and forth between different tools and programs and communication channels, write my own stuff and do it all at the same time. Bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me two days to realize that this is really stressful, unhealthy and (most embarrassing to admit) completely unnecessary. Nobody cares if I don&amp;rsquo;t show up on IRC. Nobody cares if I read their post a day later, or not at all because I missed it. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to be omnipresent and get all the information as quickly as possible, read all the articles, follow all the hashtags, answer all the posts etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to disconnect. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to only show up on IRC occasionally. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to only scroll through mastodon once or twice a day. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to not read people&amp;rsquo;s posts if I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or the energy. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to miss out on some conversations, posts, articles, videos, podcasts and whatever else is out there. And it&amp;rsquo;s also okay to post my own stuff not when I think I have to, but when it&amp;rsquo;s ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s ironic that by slowing down my computer I sped up my brain to the point where it wasn&amp;rsquo;t good for me anymore, before I realized that the slow approach also works (and works well) in other areas of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, of course I went through this cycle many, many times before, and the solution is always the same: notice it, take a deep breath, then change it. But occasionally a reminder to slow down and take a step back is needed, and this challenge certainly served as one :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 13:50:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On this day I was sick, so not a lot has happened, but I would like to still briefly share a few thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m spending far less time aimlessly surfing the web or watching youtube-videos for hours on end, simply because it&amp;rsquo;s not very much fun. Surfing works, but most sites are not very pleasant to look at or don&amp;rsquo;t work at all in a minimalist browser (think lynx, links2, luakit) or they slow the computer down to a crawl when using vivaldi (which is already slow thanks to its significant memory footprint). Important lesson: don&amp;rsquo;t have more than one or two tabs open at once. Just don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And watching youtube is pretty much impossible. Even just loading the start page takes forever, and trying to load a video&amp;hellip; just no. I had downloaded yt-dlp beforehand to be able to download yt-videos at a lower resolution, but I would still have to get the url from somewhere and honestly, I don&amp;rsquo;t even miss it. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll eventually catch up on a few interesting videos that I missed during the week, but right now I&amp;rsquo;m completely fine without spending the evening on my couch aimlessly browsing youtube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A win in my opinion!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For fun I fired up a VM (one core slowed down, 512mb RAM of course) with Windows XP and browsed some old sites via &lt;a href=&#34;https://theoldnet.com&#34;&gt;the old net&lt;/a&gt; using Retrozilla, and that turned out to be a surprising amount of fun! Retrozilla is also able to access gopher sites, and since most of the OCC-participants who run blogs keep them very minimal, starting at &lt;a href=&#34;https://occ.deadnet.se&#34;&gt;occ.deadnet.se&lt;/a&gt; and looking through the blog entries listed there was no problem at all. And &lt;strong&gt;way&lt;/strong&gt; faster than doing the same thing on a modern linux, despite a minimalist window manager and a lightweight browser (Midori). I even managed to install an old version of mIRC and join #oldcomputerchallenge on libera.chat, which was very surprising but pretty awesome and gave me a huge nostalgia hit :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putty still works on XP as well, so I can ssh into my &amp;ldquo;server&amp;rdquo; (a raspberry pi really) and do linux-y stuff on there. All in all a surprisingly nice and nostalgic experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I also switched my window manager from i3 to herbstluftwm. Why? First, I had already used herbstluftwm before and am familiar with how it works, and second, I like the name :) (for the non-German speaking world, &amp;ldquo;Herbstluft&amp;rdquo; means &amp;ldquo;autumn air&amp;rdquo;, which I think is just beautiful. Once I figure out how to post audio on here, I&amp;rsquo;ll put a file online with the correct pronounciation ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 18:00:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 2 is coming to a close. Today I was at work all day and so didn&amp;rsquo;t spend a whole lot of time on my slow computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, A thought occurred to me recently, because since I subscribed to mastodon a couple of weeks ago and especially since I started following some retro computing related postings (where I discoved the OCC in the first place), I discovered that there&amp;rsquo;s a thing called&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://communitywiki.org/static/SmolNet.html&#34;&gt;The SmolNet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is it? Well, according to the link above&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “smol” net is the “small” net. It’s small because it is build for friends and friends of friends. It doesn’t have to scale to millions of people because those millions should build their own local small nets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this help explaining it? No?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, if you&amp;rsquo;re in or approaching middle age right now, you probably remember the internet of the 90s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re too young for that, this might sound like grandpa telling stories about the war, but there was a time when the internet was young and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t yet entirely run by a handful of gigantic evil megacorporations (Amazon, Google, Facebook&amp;hellip;). Back then, people used to meet and chat on forums or IRC or BBSes (bulletin boards, but that was even before my time), and they would code their own personal websites and build communities and exchange their thoughts and ideas in this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came the web 2.0 with Facebook, Twitter, Youtube, Instagram etc., which opened the web up to the masses, but it also ushered in an era where everyone was on the same few platforms and where everyone&amp;rsquo;s profile looks like everyone elses because that was what the platform dictated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then &lt;strong&gt;The Algorithm&lt;/strong&gt; was introduced and turned the internet into a miserable and dystopian hellscape filled with online bullying and hatred and outrage because that&amp;rsquo;s what gets peoples attention and is good for the bank accounts of the Zuckerbergs and Dorseys and Musks of the world, but bad for essentially the rest of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s where we&amp;rsquo;re still at today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In between the cracks of this modern, corporatized, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pluralistic.net/2023/01/21/potemkin-ai/#hey-guys&#34;&gt;enshittified&lt;/a&gt; internet where everything looks the same and everyone is out to get your data and track you and bombard you with ads there is a small world where the internet of old still (or again?) exists. Where people build small websites, talk on IRC or BBSes, and use old protocols like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gopher_(protocol)&#34;&gt;gopher&lt;/a&gt; (or modernized versions like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gemini_(protocol)&#34;&gt;gemini&lt;/a&gt;) and exchange information in this way, far away from the walled gardens of Facebook, Twitter and such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like it was when the internet was new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet of old is still alive today. You just have to look in the right places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I think this is beautiful, and it makes me happy, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I discovered it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s explore it some more on day 3 :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 09:46:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, Day 1 is almost over, what have we learned?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern software sucks!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really, a lot of it is quite beautiful and easy to use, but boy, everything consumes so many resources! Just starting up a web browser (firefox or chrome doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter) takes a good ten seconds or more, and then we haven&amp;rsquo;t even loaded a single page yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And webpages are also so slow and bloated these days! I haven&amp;rsquo;t limited my bandwidth thankfully (otherwise I&amp;rsquo;d go completely crazy), but just trying to open any normal page I can watch the CPU hang at 100% load for 10, 20, 30 seconds even, and the memory consumption goes up and up and up&amp;hellip;. For comparison I installed Windows XP in a VM with the exact same settings as my modern linux (1 core, limited to 50%, 512mb RAM) and it runs! Installed retrozilla browser, and that is lightning fast as well (though not terribly useful any more because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t render modern sites very well&amp;hellip;. and let&amp;rsquo;s not even think about security). This just shows how much more resource-hungry everything has become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, sidenote: I noticed that this site here doesn&amp;rsquo;t render very well on old browsers either, and on links2 (console-based browser) it isn&amp;rsquo;t useable at all because the links to the posts are not accessible. Ups&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t know enough HTML to fix this though, so this is a problem for future me. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll have it sorted for the next OCC in a year ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About sites like YouTube&amp;hellip; yeah, best not to talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening to a podcast was fine though, I downloaded it through gpodder, copied it to my iPod and enjoyed it free of distraction on my couch :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plans for the upcoming days:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figure out more console based alternatives to the software I normally use (browser, podcatcher, mastodon-client, mail-client etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dive a bit more into Windows XP, if for nothing more than nostalgia&amp;rsquo;s sake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try not to go crazy with everything being so slow! :P&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Preparation</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 09:46:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-preparation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year I learned about &lt;a href=&#34;https://bsd.network/@solene&#34;&gt;Solene&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataswamp.org/~solene/2023-06-04-old-computer-challenge-v3.html&#34;&gt;Old Computer Challenge&lt;/a&gt;, and I thought hey, I might give it a go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this year the rules for the challenge are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s use a SLOW computer for 7 days. This will be achieved by various means with any hardware:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limit your computer&amp;rsquo;s CPU to use only 1 core. This can be set in the BIOS most of the time, and on Linux you can use &lt;code&gt;maxcores=1&lt;/code&gt; in the boot command line, on OpenBSD you can use &lt;code&gt;bsd.sp&lt;/code&gt; kernel for the duration of the challenge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limit your computer&amp;rsquo;s memory to 512 MB of memory (no swap limit). This can be set on Linux using the boot command line &lt;code&gt;mem=512MB&lt;/code&gt;. On OpenBSD, this can be achieved a bit similarly by using &lt;code&gt;datasize-max=512M&lt;/code&gt; in login.conf for your user&amp;rsquo;s login class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set your CPU frequency to the lowest minimum (which is pretty low on modern hardware!). On Linux, use the &amp;ldquo;powersave&amp;rdquo; frequency governor, in modern desktop environments the battery widget should offer an easy way to set the governor. On OpenBSD, run &lt;code&gt;apm -L&lt;/code&gt; (while apmd service is running). On Windows, in the power settings, set the frequency to minimum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, easy enough, right? Well, of course my natural tendency to overthink everything kicked in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I thought, I&amp;rsquo;d fire up my (almost) 20 year old laptop from back when I was in university. Turns out, the thing is really on its last legs, the battery has died long ago, the display hinges are barely holding together, the backlight (CFL, no LEDs) could give up at any moment&amp;hellip; not a pleasant experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://82mhz.net/aspire2001.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Acer Aspire 2001&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d just slow down my normal desktop PC to one core, 512mb RAM and limit the cpu frequency&amp;hellip; but that didn&amp;rsquo;t really feel old, it was just my normal computer a bit slower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after a lot of thinking what I ended up with is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep my desktop computer off for the week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use only my Laptop (a 2013 (or 2014?) 13 inch Macbook Air, almost old and vintage itself!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a VM in Virtualbox with 512mb RAM, one cpu core and limit the core to 50% speed (I have no idea how slow this actually is compared to a proper old computer, but it does feel slow, and that&amp;rsquo;s the point, right?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Endeavouros (an Arch Linux variant) with the i3 window manager and use mostly terminal apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For fun, I also installed a second VM (same specs as above) with Windows XP for that authentic retro-feeling (I used it back in the day before I switched to Linux in 2008 or so)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminate browsing and YouTube on my smartphone (because otherwise I would just use this all week) and only use the phone as a communication device, meaning only for SMS, WhatsApp, E-Mail and (shocker!) even as a proper telephone!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music comes from physical media, meaning CDs, vinyl, radio or an old iPod (yes, I&amp;rsquo;m lumping the iPod in with the physical media because it&amp;rsquo;s a dedicated device whose only purpose is to play music - and most importantly it can&amp;rsquo;t go online!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is the setup for now, we&amp;rsquo;ll see how the week goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://82mhz.net/oldComputerSetup.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Setup for the OldComputerChallenge&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the fun begin!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
