<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>website on 82MHz</title>
    <link>https://82mhz.net/tags/website/</link>
    <description>Recent content in website on 82MHz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://82mhz.net/tags/website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The books I read in October 2023</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/11/the-books-i-read-in-october-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/11/the-books-i-read-in-october-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In October I read two non-fiction books I only recently came across, and one novel that I&amp;rsquo;ve had for quite a while and which I wanted to read to relax, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t turn out to be so relaxing in the end&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;https://82mhz.net/images/buecherokt2023.png&#34; max-height=&#34;400x&#34;/&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;menn&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Joseph Menn&lt;/em&gt;: Cult of the Dead Cow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cult of the Dead Cow is a loosely organized hacker collective originally from Texas that has been around since the late 70s and is still active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d never heard of them until recently, when they announced the development of &lt;a href=&#34;https://veilid.com/&#34;&gt;Veilid&lt;/a&gt;, an encrypted P2P network, so I wanted to know who and what they were about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book goes through the history of the collective from its beginnings to the present. They started out, like so many hackers of the time, as teenagers who tricked the American phone system to make free phone calls or access BBS systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always find it exciting to read stories about the early days of computers and hacking, but for me they are mainly historical stories, as I am too young to have experienced it all myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore the book became really interesting for me in the second half, from the late 90s onwards, where it covers events that I can actually remember from being online myself. Events and names like George W. Bush as US president, 9/11, Wikileaks, Assange, Snowden, the drama surrounding Jacob Applebaum etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, an exciting and entertaining read if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in underground hacker culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;voss&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chris Voss&lt;/em&gt;: Never split the Difference&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Voss was the FBI&amp;rsquo;s chief negotiator for hostage-taking and kidnappings for years. He was the guy who was sent in when Al-Qaeda or some other fundamentalists kidnapped US-Americans and threatened to kill them if their demands were not met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the book, he summarizes his knowledge and presents his method for keeping a cool head in negotiations and getting the best out of the negotiation for yourself (in the case of hostage takings, of course, the release of the hostage with as little or no ransom money paid as possible).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core of his methodology is what he calls &amp;ldquo;tactical empathy&amp;rdquo;, which is ultimately just empathy, seeing the world from the other person&amp;rsquo;s perspective and understanding where they&amp;rsquo;re coming from and what drives them. Because you can only negotiate successfully once you have understood your negotiating partner&amp;rsquo;s motivation and have recognized what they are really concerned about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title &amp;ldquo;Never split the Difference&amp;rdquo; sounds crass at first, but it also makes sense, as by his definition splitting the difference is something that both sides are dissatisfied with, whereas the result of a successful negotiation should be that both sides are satisfied with the outcome and no one feels that they have been taken advantage of or have allowed themselves to be manipulated into doing things that they didn&amp;rsquo;t actually want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very good book and, unlike many other non fiction books, it is really packed with information and does have a lot to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;harris&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thomas Harris&lt;/em&gt;: Roter Drache (Red Dragon)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas Harris is the author of the novels &amp;ldquo;The Silence of the Lambs&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Hannibal&amp;rdquo;, both of which I read many years ago, and I also saw the movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Silence of the Lambs was fantastic, both the book and the movie, Hannibal I found both rather disappointing, and after Hannibal there was also a movie adaptation of Red Dragon (a remake to be precise, because the book had already been adapted into a movie called &amp;ldquo;Manhunter&amp;rdquo;), which I think I might have seen in the cinema at the time, but of which I only remember that Anthony Hopkins looks much older than in Silence of the Lambs, although the story takes place before that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I had never read the book &amp;ldquo;Red Dragon&amp;rdquo;, so now was the time to catch up. After all the non-fiction books I&amp;rsquo;ve read recently, I felt like reading a novel again to relax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it didn&amp;rsquo;t turn out to be very relaxing because the story is extremely thrilling and atmospherically dense, so much so that I had to read the second half of the book outside my normal reading time (in bed at night) because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t put it down and my sleep suffered as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A psychopathic murderer is on the loose, wiping out entire families and leaving his trademark teeth marks on the victims, which is why the media call him &amp;ldquo;Tooth Fairy&amp;rdquo;, which has unfortunately and disastrously been translated as &amp;ldquo;Tooth Faggot&amp;rdquo; into German - and it is mentioned A LOT. Makes reading it a bit challenging&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, FBI investigator Will Graham is put on the case, who (before the events in the book) had already arrested Hannibal Lecter, which almost cost him his life and after which he had retired with his family. However, as he has the ability to empathize with psychopaths and understand their motives better than anyone else, he is reactivated by FBI agent Jack Crawford. So he begins to delve into the case and soon realizes that he needs Dr. Lecter&amp;rsquo;s help to get into the head of the Tooth Fairy&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was struck by the book&amp;rsquo;s clear parallels with &amp;ldquo;Silence of the Lambs&amp;rdquo;, which was published a few years later. In both books, a psychopathic killer is leaving a trail of bodies behind, and the FBI has to put a stop to him under enormous time pressure before he strikes again, which is why the imprisoned Dr. Lecter, equal parts psychopath and brilliant analyst, is asked for help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the stories and characters are different enough to stand on their own. Will Graham and the Tooth Fairy are great antagonists, even if the book spends a little too much time with the killer in its second half for my taste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post 012/100 of the 100DaysToOffload-Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Bye, Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/11/good-bye-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/11/good-bye-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a Raspberry Pi 4 as my homeserver, it&amp;rsquo;s running off an SD card. Or it was, because the SD card died recently, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day I woke up to the server not responding, and a reboot didn&amp;rsquo;t help either. So I attached a monitor and found that the Pi was stuck in the &amp;ldquo;bios&amp;rdquo;, telling me that it couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the SD card, even though it was plugged in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I looked at the card on my normal PC and found that it was recognized as a drive with 0 bytes. Not great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I googled for a while to see if there was a way to revive the card, and I also asked on mastodon if anyone had an idea, but the responses were&amp;hellip; not encouraging. Seems like the card is dead and at least with normal methods there is no way to restore it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-happened-and-what-next&#34;&gt;What happened, and what next?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I can&amp;rsquo;t look at any logs anymore, figuring out what happened is pure speculation. Someone on mastodon suggested that it might be excessive writes to the card due to the USB-stick RAID array I set up. Maybe that was the case, I don&amp;rsquo;t know. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware that a RAID can cause excessive writes to the system disk, but it could have been. Could have also been a power loss during a write and that corrupted the card&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this is not the first time that&amp;rsquo;s happened. I have a Raspi 4 at work that already killed two cards during normal operation, and there I was also not able to determine what had happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could have been a problem with the cards, or with the Raspi, or a power failure, or a fault with the hardware that was plugged into it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that I&amp;rsquo;m starting to lose trust in Rasperry Pis, especially since there are a ton of posts online about Raspis killing SD cards&amp;hellip; and of course I have backups and everything, so no data was lost, but setting it all up again is still a pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-server&#34;&gt;New server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a bit annoyed with the Raspi anyway, because I use docker a lot for the services I&amp;rsquo;m running, and I often found that docker images weren&amp;rsquo;t available for ARM at all or not for the specific ARM version the Pi is using, so I was already thinking about switching to x86, and this event finalized the decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My idea was to get either a SFF machine or an old laptop, so I can set up a server that consumes as little power as possible. I looked around on classified ads and found an old Dell Latitude E7440 with an i5 4200U mobile processor, 8GB RAM and 128GB SSD from a local guy, which is just about perfect for my usecase, so I bought it straight away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so here we are, an old business laptop is my new server!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of setting it back up and (a first for me, but essential) documenting every step of the way in the form of a bash script that I can just run if I want to install a new server, and everything will be set up the way it was in no time. At least that&amp;rsquo;s my goal, we&amp;rsquo;ll see if I achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post 011/100 of the 100DaysToOffload-Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using two USB Sticks as a Raid on a Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/10/using-two-usb-sticks-as-a-raid-on-a-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/10/using-two-usb-sticks-as-a-raid-on-a-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day I mentioned in passing on Mastodon that I am using two USB-Sticks as a RAID array on my homeserver, which is a Raspberry Pi 4. Much to my surprise, two people actually asked how this was done, so I promised I would write it up as a blog post. And so here we are. Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;m not an IT expert, some things in this tutorial could be wrong or even lead to data loss, so use the information here at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, what is a RAID? RAID stands for &amp;ldquo;redundant array of independent disks&amp;rdquo;, which simply means that more than one physical drive are connected together to form one logical drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a variety of different ways to set this up, called RAID levels, which I won&amp;rsquo;t get into here, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RAID&#34;&gt;wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; and many other pages have you covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up my USB sticks as a RAID 1 array, which means the data is mirrored across two (could also be more than two for extra redundancy) drives and they all contain the exact same information. This way, if one drive fails, the other still has everything saved and no data is lost. Of course when this happens, the faulty drive needs to be replaced as soon as possible before the other one fails as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got two inexpensive Sandisk 64GB USB drives from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.de/SanDisk-Ultra-Flair-USB-Flash-Laufwerk-150-MB/dp/B015CH1NAQ/ref=sr_1_3?__mk_de_DE=%C3%85M%C3%85%C5%BD%C3%95%C3%91&amp;amp;crid=2KRIYR2F3VF31&amp;amp;keywords=64gb+sandisk+usb&amp;amp;qid=1697862134&amp;amp;sprefix=64gb+sandisk+usb%2Caps%2C205&amp;amp;sr=8-3&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; that I connected to my Raspi and set up as a RAID 1 array. This is not a buying recommendation by the way, but I never had a problem with Sandisk drives in the past and these were reasonably cheap, so I went with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plugged them into my Raspi, and that&amp;rsquo;s the hardware setup taken care of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-configuration&#34;&gt;Software configuration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll walk through the installation here, for reference a list of all the commands is at the &lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34;&gt;bottom of the post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The raid is configured through a utility called &amp;lsquo;mdadm&amp;rsquo;, which you can install through the packet manager of your distro or compile from scratch if you&amp;rsquo;re hardcore. I&amp;rsquo;m not hardcore, so I simply installed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt install mdadm
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, I checked if the USB drives are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ lsblk
NAME        MAJ:MIN RM  SIZE RO TYPE MOUNTPOINT
sda           8:0    1 57,3G  0 disk 
sdb           8:16   1 57,3G  0 disk 
mmcblk0     179:0    0 29,1G  0 disk 
├─mmcblk0p1 179:1    0  256M  0 part /boot
└─mmcblk0p2 179:2    0 28,9G  0 part /
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can see they&amp;rsquo;re connected as drives sda and sdb, so I&amp;rsquo;m good to continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next command creates the RAID array, level 1 (mirrored) from the two USB devices. Make sure you use the correct device names!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo mdadm --create --verbose /dev/md0 --level=1 --raid-devices=2 /dev/sda /dev/sdb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the output from the command, it tells me that the drives already have a  partition table, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter because they will be reformatted, and asks me to confirm. Then it returns to the console and the array is created in the background:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo mdadm --create --verbose /dev/md0 --level=1 --raid-devices=2 /dev/sda /dev/sdb
mdadm: partition table exists on /dev/sda
mdadm: partition table exists on /dev/sda but will be lost or
       meaningless after creating array
mdadm: Note: this array has metadata at the start and
    may not be suitable as a boot device.  If you plan to
    store &amp;#39;/boot&amp;#39; on this device please ensure that
    your boot-loader understands md/v1.x metadata, or use
    --metadata=0.90
mdadm: partition table exists on /dev/sdb
mdadm: partition table exists on /dev/sdb but will be lost or
       meaningless after creating array
mdadm: size set to 60029952K
Continue creating array? (y/n) y
mdadm: Defaulting to version 1.2 metadata
mdadm: array /dev/md0 started.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reading the file &amp;lsquo;/proc/mdstat&amp;rsquo; shows the progress of this operation, depending on the size and speed of the drives this can take a long time, for my two 64GB USB sticks it took about an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cat /proc/mdstat
Personalities : [raid1] 
md0 : active raid1 sdb[1] sda[0]
      60029952 blocks super 1.2 [2/2] [UU]
      [&amp;gt;....................]  resync =  0.5% (336448/60029952) finish=62.0min speed=16021K/sec
      
unused devices: &amp;lt;none&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I followed the process with the &amp;lsquo;watch&amp;rsquo; command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ watch &amp;#39;cat /proc/mdstat&amp;#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the tutorial I followed, I can start using the array even before it is fully assembled, so the next thing I needed to do was to format the new file system:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo mkfs.ext4 -F /dev/md0
mke2fs 1.46.2 (28-Feb-2021)
/dev/md0 contains a ext4 file system
	last mounted on Fri Oct 20 11:48:52 2023
Creating filesystem with 15007488 4k blocks and 3751936 inodes
Filesystem UUID: 2361e08e-3703-46f5-b425-ad4d519b555c
Superblock backups stored on blocks: 
	32768, 98304, 163840, 229376, 294912, 819200, 884736, 1605632, 2654208, 
	4096000, 7962624, 11239424

Allocating group tables: done                            
Writing inode tables: done                            
Creating journal (65536 blocks): 
done
Writing superblocks and filesystem accounting information: done   
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I then created a mount point and mounted the new drive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo mkdir -p /mnt/md0
$ sudo mount /dev/md0 /mnt/md0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;And looking at my drives with &amp;lsquo;df&amp;rsquo;, I can see that the array is mounted and ready to use (shortened for readability):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ df -h
Dateisystem    Typ      Größe Benutzt Verf. Verw% Eingehängt auf
...
/dev/md0       ext4       57G     24K   54G    1% /mnt/md0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s almost all, just a few small things need to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, save the array configuration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo mdadm --detail --scan | sudo tee -a /etc/mdadm/mdadm.conf
ARRAY /dev/md0 metadata=1.2 name=pi4srv:0 UUID=402c7741:7e70698e:b2ed9be5:c6e3531e
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add the array to fstab so it is automatically mounted at startup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ echo &amp;#39;/dev/md0 /mnt/md0 ext4 rw,user,exec,defaults,nofail,discard 0 0&amp;#39; | sudo tee -a /etc/fstab
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;And change the access rights of the mount folder so a regular user can write to it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo chmod 777 /mnt/md0/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;And with that, I have a working RAID 1 array consisting of two cheap USB drives running on my Raspberry Pi homeserver, which I can use for backup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How reliable these drives are and how long they last I have no idea, time will tell. But that&amp;rsquo;s why I got two, if one fails I&amp;rsquo;ll hopefully have time to replace it before the other fails as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m planning to mirror my server config files and docker setup from the internal SD card to this external storage, and also use it to backup and distribute important files across my home network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I do this though, I want to test what happens if one of the drives &amp;lsquo;fails&amp;rsquo; and how the data can be accessed/restored in this case. A backup is only a backup if it can be restored after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m still in the process of setting this all up, so that might be a topic for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the list of commands I ran for future reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo mdadm --create --verbose /dev/md0 --level=1 --raid-devices=2 /dev/sda /dev/sdb #make sure you have the correct devices selected
cat /proc/mdstat
sudo mkfs.ext4 -F /dev/md0
sudo mkdir -p /mnt/md0
sudo mount /dev/md0 /mnt/md0
sudo mdadm --detail --scan | sudo tee -a /etc/mdadm/mdadm.conf
echo &amp;#39;/dev/md0 /mnt/md0 ext4 rw,user,exec,defaults,nofail,discard 0 0&amp;#39; | sudo tee -a /etc/fstab
sudo chmod 777 /mnt/md0/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-create-raid-arrays-with-mdadm-on-ubuntu-22-04&#34;&gt;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-create-raid-arrays-with-mdadm-on-ubuntu-22-04&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://serverfault.com/questions/32709/how-do-i-move-a-linux-software-raid-to-a-new-machine&#34;&gt;https://serverfault.com/questions/32709/how-do-i-move-a-linux-software-raid-to-a-new-machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post 010/100 of the 100DaysToOffload-Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living in the (technological) past</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/10/living-in-the-technological-past/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/10/living-in-the-technological-past/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about it for a while now, and a conversation yesterday with &lt;a href=&#34;https://alpha.polymaths.social/@roguefoam&#34;&gt;Rogue&lt;/a&gt; over on Mastodon brought it to my attention again: I&amp;rsquo;ve never been an early adopter of anything tech related. I live in the technological past. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore if this is a good or a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I look around my apartment, most of the electronic devices that I own are far from new, and were not even new when I bought them, because I got them used when they were already several years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My TV is a used 46&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; plasma that I got from my uncle around 2014 or so.
My smartphone is a used Samsung Galaxy S10e from 2019 that I got off Ebay.
My laptop is a 2014 Macbook Air running linux, again used from Ebay.
My headphones are Bose Quietcomfort 35 and Bose Quietcomfort Earbuds, used, Ebay.
My desktop PC was used off of Ebay years ago, but I replaced the mainboard, CPU and RAM with new components 4 years ago. Graphics card was used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My washing machine must be at least 20 years old by now, I&amp;rsquo;ve had it for about 15 years, and even my kitchen appliances (in fact my entire kitchen) came used from a young woman a few blocks away who was moving in with her boyfriend and didn&amp;rsquo;t need it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there are a few new things here and there, but most of the devices I have are years old and I didn&amp;rsquo;t buy them new in the first place. Why is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it started because back when I was in school and later on in university, I simply never had too much money. I come from a working class family, and we were far from poor, but also far from rich, so I learned to be frugal and save money early on. As a child and teenager it annoyed me of course because friends from wealthier households had a lot more toys and gadgets to play with, while my allowance was a lot smaller and I had to be mindful of what I bought and what I didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same was true in my 20s in university, I could get by with the money I had, but there was never too much left over to constantly buy new computers, phones, consoles etc. But by that time I had realized that I don&amp;rsquo;t need to be at the leading edge of technology, as a lot of my fellow students were, and I was okay with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I finished university and started working in the industry, for the first time in my life I was earning significantly more money than I was spending. But still I carried this mindset of frugality and asking myself &amp;ldquo;do I really need this&amp;rdquo; through my late 20s and 30s all the way into my early 40s, which is where I am now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, most new trends enter my life years after everyone else has already gotten on board. I was among the last in my group of friends to get a cellphone, the last to have a smartphone, I was watching movies on a CRT when everybody already had HD flatscreen TVs, and I still don&amp;rsquo;t have a smart watch, fitness tracker, 4k TV, current gen games console or whatever else is trending right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My smartphone and my desktop PC are the newest devices I own, and they&amp;rsquo;re both about 4 years old and I see no need to replace them anytime soon because they still work perfectly and do everything I need them to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I keep reading tech news and watching Youtube channels like MKBHD, so I know what&amp;rsquo;s current and I catch myself thinking &amp;ldquo;oh, I want to have that!&amp;rdquo; at times, but then I also remember that I just don&amp;rsquo;t need the thing and it&amp;rsquo;s way too expensive anyway, and then I move on with my life and keep using my old crap until it breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;rsquo;s a certain peace of mind that goes along with this mindset that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to give up anymore. I save a lot of money, a lot of mental space and maybe a bit of the environment as well. And I like it that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post 009/100 of the 100DaysToOffload-Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The books I read in September 2023</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/10/the-books-i-read-in-september-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/10/the-books-i-read-in-september-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;September was not a great reading month for me. The month started with a week of being sick, during which I couldn&amp;rsquo;t do much at all, and even after that I found it difficult to concentrate on reading. Nevertheless, I read three books (more or less), which I&amp;rsquo;ll summarise here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;https://82mhz.net/images/buecher092023.jpg&#34; max-height=&#34;400x&#34;/&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;spiegelman&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Art Spiegelman&lt;/em&gt;: Maus (Graphic Novel)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite unusual for me, this is not a &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; book, but a graphic novel instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea to read this book came from a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mikegrindle.com/posts/bannedbooks&#34;&gt;blog post by Mike Grindle&lt;/a&gt;, who was in turn inspired by an interview with Neil Gaiman, to talk about how in certain conservative areas in the US the banning of books from schools seems to be becoming more and more widespread. Quite unsurprisingly, it often affects books that teach about the Holocaust, such as Art Spiegelman&amp;rsquo;s Maus or the diary of Anne Frank - always under the pretext, of course, of having to protect the wellbeing of the children. You can&amp;rsquo;t expose the poor children to such horrifying stories, the narrative goes, and even worse, some of these books have the audacity to mention the existence of a thing called the female body - and we can&amp;rsquo;t teach that in our schools!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I would like nothing more than to laugh at the bigotry of these Americans with their ridiculous and antiquated ideas of morality, but these kinds of ideas have a tendency to spread to other parts of the world as well, even here in Europe the argument &amp;ldquo;we need to protect our children&amp;rdquo; is used quite frequently to justify legislation that limits civil rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the book, the author Art Spiegelman is the son of two Polish Jews, Vladek and Anja, who survived the Holocaust and emigrated to the USA after the war in Europe ended. He himself was born after the war, his mother committed suicide when he was a young man and he didn&amp;rsquo;t get along too well with his father. However, he was interested in learning about his father&amp;rsquo;s experiences during the holocaust and preserving them in the form of a graphic novel, so he often went to visit his father (long after his mother&amp;rsquo;s death), asking him about his life and recording the conversations on tape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These recordings then became the foundation of the graphic novel. The title stems from the fact that he draws people of different nationalities as different kinds of animals. Jews are depicted as mice, Germans, fittingly, as cats (in an early version, the mice were also much smaller than the cats to make the aggressiveness of the Germans even more obvious, in the final version they are the same size). Other nationalities are also depicted as animals, for example the French are frogs and the Poles are pigs (and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if there was a deeper meaning to this, because most of the Poles in the novel also treat the Jews pretty badly).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel has two narrative levels, the framework is how the author, Art, keeps visiting his father to get his experiences about the holocaust on tape, the second level is the story Vladek is telling him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story of Art talking to his father is already fascinating, because it gives a good insight into Arts complicated relationship with his father Vladek, who isn&amp;rsquo;t the most enjoyable person to be around (at one point Art struggles with the depiction of his dad, because he wants to show him how he really is, but realizes that Vladek is pretty much exactly the Jewish cliché of being cheap and thrifty). And one can&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if he was always like this or if his experiences have made him into the character he is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But of course the look into the past is what really makes the book unique. We learn (always from Vladek&amp;rsquo;s point of view, of course) what the situation was like in Poland before the war began, how conditions for the Jews deteriorated further and further after the German attack on Poland, and how rumours about deportations and concentration camps started to spread, but often weren&amp;rsquo;t taken seriously because it was simply inconceivable that something like that was really happening. We learn how Vladek and Anja had to give their first son away to keep him safe, and he how he didn&amp;rsquo;t survive the war regardless. And how Vladek and Anja were eventually deported by the Germans and put on trains to Auschwitz, where they were separated and each had to fight for survival in the face of the absolut horror in the camps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And no matter how many books about the holocaust I&amp;rsquo;ve read or movies I&amp;rsquo;ve watched, reading about individual people&amp;rsquo;s experiences is always terrifying. About one to 1.5 million people perished in Auschwitz, but it&amp;rsquo;s a number one can&amp;rsquo;t really grasp. Reading about what it was like from one persons point of view gives it so much more weight and realism. And a graphic novel acutally works pretty well as a medium, because you don&amp;rsquo;t just hear Vladek&amp;rsquo;s story, you can also see it in Art&amp;rsquo;s black and white images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highly recommended reading, and already a contender for best book of the year for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And shame on the people who want to restrict access to these kinds of stories for whatever twisted ideological reasons they might have. We teach the history of the Holocaust not to traumatise or terrify our children or to keep us Germans locked in a state of perpetual guilt, as some right-wing blockheads here keep repeating, but to remember what happened. To make us aware of the atrocities humans are capable of and to remind us that it is the duty of us all to prevent such things from ever happening again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;baxter&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stephen Baxter&lt;/em&gt;: Voyage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voyage is a science fiction novel of the &amp;ldquo;what if&amp;rdquo; category. In this case, what if, after the Apollo moon landings, the USA had not focused on the space shuttle program, but had set its sights on Mars as the next goal and launched a manned mission to Mars instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds exciting? I thought so too. But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book has about 900 pages (in the German edition), and I really tried to push through, but failed at around page 400 and put it aside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to give Stephen Baxter credit for having really thoroughly researched the subject, and he says himself in the foreword that his aim was to stay as close to reality as possible and to describe the Mars mission and the way to get there as realistically as possible. As far as I have read the book, he has succeeded in doing so. The only problem: I found it really boring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The characters seem clichéd and flat and uninteresting, more like archetypes than real people, and the situations and events are close to reality and could have really happened that way, but unfortunately they are also not exciting at all. I think I spent about 14 days reading the book, but I never managed more than a dozen or so pages at a time, because it just didn&amp;rsquo;t grab me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And instead of sinking more time into it, I decided to put it aside. Maybe the second half will be better and more exciting, but the first half didn&amp;rsquo;t captivate me at all, so I won&amp;rsquo;t find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;allen&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;David Allen&lt;/em&gt;: Getting Things Done&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think there&amp;rsquo;s much that I can write about Getting Things Done that hasn&amp;rsquo;t already been written a thousand times somewhere else or described in countless YouTube videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now, the book has become a classic of productivity literature, and for good reason, but also (for me) with a huge catch: it is complex. Just reading through the 300-plus pages takes quite some time, and really understanding the system (let alone actually implementing it!) takes even longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to read the book mainly because I&amp;rsquo;ve never read it and I wanted to know what the system was really about. Until now I only knew articles and videos about it, but that&amp;rsquo;s not the same as reading the book itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic idea is to get everything that requires planning or any kind of action out of your head and into a system that you trust and that you know won&amp;rsquo;t lose any important information, so you can relax and feel less stressed about trying to remember a thousand different things at any one time. And I have to say, yes, it does seem like a well thought out and complete system for organising and taking control of your work and life, as the title promises. But no, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to implement it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least not in its full form, because it&amp;rsquo;s just too complex for me and there are some things I probably didn&amp;rsquo;t understand too well either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what I will take away from the book and what I will try to implement is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only things that &lt;strong&gt;have&lt;/strong&gt; to be done on that exact day go into the calendar. If you use the calendar as a kind of to-do list, you water it down and you trust it less&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For each project (for David Allen, almost everything is a project), it must be clearly defined what the next actionable step is. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to plan the whole project step by step, but the next concrete step has to be clearly described&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need a filing system for digital content. PDFs, links, web pages etc&amp;hellip;. I try to remember too many things, and even when I save something, it&amp;rsquo;s often in a random location that I won&amp;rsquo;t remember a week from now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need a waiting-for system, i.e. for things where I need to wait for someone else&amp;rsquo;s input or that I can&amp;rsquo;t do until later, I need a system that reminds me at the right time and that I can trust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I should define some &amp;ldquo;inboxes&amp;rdquo; that I work through every day and put the contents in appropriate places. E.g. one inbox on the PC, one on the desk, one on the mobile phone for when I&amp;rsquo;m on the go&amp;hellip;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have to set aside some time each day to empty the inboxes. I&amp;rsquo;m currently trying weekly reviews, but they&amp;rsquo;re not working super well for me, so maybe daily inbox processing is better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: For me personally, I think the system has some interesting approaches, but as a whole it is too complex for me. Nevertheless, it was good to have read the book to get an overview of how David Allen himself describes his system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post 008/100 of the 100DaysToOffload-Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ongoing Enshittification of Whatsapp</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/the-ongoing-enshittification-of-whatsapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/the-ongoing-enshittification-of-whatsapp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago Whatsapp renamed the status page to &amp;ldquo;Updates&amp;rdquo; and introduced the &amp;ldquo;Channels&amp;rdquo; feature. And suddenly, the messenger I use to communicate with friends and family shows me recommendations for profiles of people and corporations I don&amp;rsquo;t know and don&amp;rsquo;t want to hear from. I don&amp;rsquo;t like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already know the channels feature from Telegram, where they are used by conspiracy theorists, covid deniers and straight up right-wing extremists to reach their followers. And probably by some normal people who just want to connect with other people as well, the world isn&amp;rsquo;t just black and white, good and evil after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course Meta thought, we need to have this feature as well! Even if it has the potential to be just as problematic as the channels on Telegram (and maybe even more so, because Whatsapp has a much broader user base, at least here in Germany). But Facebook is no stranger to their plattform causing social unrest, to put it mildly, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2022/09/myanmar-facebooks-systems-promoted-violence-against-rohingya-meta-owes-reparations-new-report/&#34;&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s the worst that could happen&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, for a few days now I&amp;rsquo;ve been finding recommendations in my Whatsapp app (yes) to follow the channels of various football clubs, influencers and corporations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I want this? No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can I turn it off? No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this going to get more intrusive and aggressive as time moves on? You bet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with that, the enshittification of Whatsapp is in full swing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is enshittification? &lt;a href=&#34;https://craphound.com/news/2023/02/20/tiktoks-enshittification/&#34;&gt;The term was coined by Cory Doctorow&lt;/a&gt;, he uses it to describe the seemingly inevitable decline of well-liked platforms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how platforms die: first, they are good to their users; then they abuse their users to make things better for their business customers; finally, they abuse those business customers to claw back all the value for themselves. Then, they die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I call this enshittification [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest victim of this process (from my own personal point of view) is Whatsapp, but for me, they were already on my &amp;ldquo;shitlist&amp;rdquo; anyway, on the one hand because of the unbearable behavior of Facebook, which by now &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/-/de/dp/B07YSHD2C5/ref=sr_1_23?__mk_de_DE=%C3%85M%C3%85%C5%BD%C3%95%C3%91&amp;amp;keywords=facebook&amp;amp;qid=1695806285&amp;amp;sr=8-23&#34;&gt;fills&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/-/de/dp/B0BHSNK6BV/ref=sr_1_18?__mk_de_DE=%C3%85M%C3%85%C5%BD%C3%95%C3%91&amp;amp;keywords=facebook&amp;amp;qid=1695806285&amp;amp;sr=8-18&#34;&gt;entire&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/-/de/dp/B07V8CL7RH/ref=sr_1_8?__mk_de_DE=%C3%85M%C3%85%C5%BD%C3%95%C3%91&amp;amp;keywords=facebook&amp;amp;qid=1695806285&amp;amp;sr=8-8&#34;&gt;books&lt;/a&gt;, and on the other hand because they have been announcing for years now that ads will be shown in Whatsapp at some point. So it was only a matter of time before it happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this made me think about the past&amp;hellip; in my last post I wrote a bit about my favorite messenger from the old days, ICQ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICQ was great, had a simple interface, you could use it to chat with your friends and that was it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginning yes, the interfaces of the early ICQ versions were simple and functional. Contact list, chat window for each contact, that&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICQ started in 1996 as a product of a small Israeli startup called Mirabilis, but already in 1998 it was acquired by one of the largest corporations at the time, AOL. At first, the messenger remained simple and limited to its core functionality, but since the early 2000s, the interface became increasingly (and annoyingly) colorful with more and more unnccessary bling and useless features, ads, online games, etc., until the app was virtually unusable and users migrated to other platforms. I remember using third-party apps for a while to retain the simple and unintrusive interface of the past. ICQ was eventually sold on to a Russian company and continues to exist in Russia to this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And somehow the story of Whatsapp looks very similar. It was founded by a small startup and then taken over by a huge tech company for an &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.fb.com/news/2014/02/facebook-to-acquire-whatsapp/&#34;&gt;insane amount of money&lt;/a&gt;. At first, the app remained pretty much as it was and even got some useful features (end-to-end encryption, for instance), but for some time now Meta has been dedicating more resources to &amp;ldquo;developing&amp;rdquo; the platform, and the user experience has been getting worse and worse (again, in my personal opinion).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that leaves me wondering, is this process inevitable? Does this happen to all popular platforms at some point? And what can we, the users, do about it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I can now leave Whatsapp and migrate to Signal or Threema, both of which I already use and both of which are still quite &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo; and focus on their core functionalities, but will it stay that way? Who can guarantee that the companies running these platforms won&amp;rsquo;t decide tomorrow or next week or next year to serve me ads or to push some profiles in my face that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to see? And then, what&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are we doomed to migrate from platform to platform for the rest of our lives because everything will eventually go to the shit and become an unusable mess because of feature creep and enshittification?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, I don&amp;rsquo;t have an answer to these questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post 007/100 of the 100DaysToOffload Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a translation of the original German post made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; and then manually adapted to (hopefully) sound a bit more human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Relationship with digital Communication - the Beginnings</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/my-relationship-with-digital-communication-the-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/my-relationship-with-digital-communication-the-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Around 1999, the future arrived in our home: From then on, we had internet access, and quite unusual for the time, not via modem, but via ISDN with a terrific speed of 64kBit/s! While the others were still using their ancient 56k modems, we were already surfing the information superhighway with the speed of tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; ok, to be honest it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that much better, but an interesting long-term effect is that the typical modem noises don&amp;rsquo;t trigger any nostalgia in me because I never even got to hear them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-beginnings-e-mail-and-icq-and-a-little-bit-of-msn&#34;&gt;The beginnings: e-mail and ICQ (and a little bit of MSN)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first digital communication medium I used was the good old e-mail. At first, I used the e-mail account we got from our provider until I registered my first e-mail address, which I still have and use to this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little later, ICQ came along, because a few school friends were using it. And what a fascinating thing it was, a whole new world! Suddenly you could just go online, and the people you saw all day at school were also online, and you could just chat with each other, for hours! It was terrific. Even though I lack nostalgia for modem sounds, the &amp;ldquo;uh-OH&amp;rdquo; ICQ notification sound triggers heaps of nostalgic feelings for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MSN was also there somehow, because a few people had it, but I can hardly remember it at all. There&amp;rsquo;s only one thing I still remember: you could make phone calls via MSN, even videocalls if you had a webcam. The quality was awful of course, but it was still cool and somehow futuristic, suddenly you could see the person you were talking to!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that time, mobile phones were not yet very widespread, and as a high school student I had no money for one and no need for one anyway, so sending text messages and e-mails was only possible on the computer at home, which was in my room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-mobile-age-mobile-phones-and-sms-messages&#34;&gt;The mobile age: mobile phones and SMS messages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2003, at the age of 21, I moved out into the world, i.e. from my tiny village to the city, to start university. Up until then, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a mobile phone, nor did most of my friends. There was simply no reason for me to get one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That changed quickly at university, where you meet lots of new people all the time and they all have their mobile phones and exchange numbers and form networks this way. So I got one, too, and for the first time I could be reached outside of home too, both by phone and by text message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a side note, in the early days you could also send a limited number of SMS messages via ICQ (for free!), which I used a few times in my school days to arrange things with friends who already had a mobile phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that time, mobile phone calls were still quite expensive and each text message cost 19 cents if I remember correctly, if not 39 cents - usually you got a few free text messages from your provider and then you had to pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I always had my mobile phone with me, but I used it very little (compared to today), maybe a few dozen text messages and a handful of calls a month. Mainly just to quickly agree on a time and place to meet up with people, but not to have longer conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more extensive text communication, I still used ICQ at that time, and a little later also the chat feature of Skype, and of course e-mail was still the medium of choice for longer letters and I used it to keep in touch with old friends who had moved to other cities or stayed at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my digital communication slowly intensified, but it still mainly took place on the PC, which was now a laptop, but (as laptops of the 2000s were) it was big and heavy and bulky and therefore it mostly lived on the desk in my tiny little students apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s how it was pretty much through my entire time at university and into the 2010s. The laptop and mobile phone were replaced by more modern models at some point, but mobile internet was insanely expensive in Germany in the 2000s, and text messages and phone calls weren&amp;rsquo;t exactly cheap either, so I stuck with what I knew: ICQ, Skype, e-mails from home, SMS and the occasional quick call on the go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;brief-interlude-studivz-and-facebook&#34;&gt;Brief Interlude: StudiVZ and Facebook&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometime in 2006, &amp;ldquo;StudiVZ&amp;rdquo; arrived in my life, a German 1:1 clone of Facebook (and consequently there were sued by Facebook for it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we all went completely nuts. It was the first &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; social network to appear on my radar, and also the first (and only) really usable one for me, because for a short while virtually everyone I knew was on there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But StudiVZ went down the drain relatively quickly, partly because of Facebook&amp;rsquo;s lawsuit, and Facebook also took over and started to dominate the market here in Germany. I also made an account there, but I never felt particularly comfortable on the platform, and when they made the switch to an algorithmically sorted timeline, I had enough and I left the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, beginning with StudiVZ and even more so with Facebook, I started to be more and more concerned with online privacy and I became much more sensitive to what I was actually revealing about myself to the world and to the owners of the platforms I was on, and in whose hands these data would end up. So even back then I was careful not to share too much of my life online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then smartphones came along and changed everything. But this article is at a 1000 words already, so that will be a story for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post 006/100 of the 100DaysToOffload Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a translation of the original German post made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; and then manually adapted to (hopefully) sound a bit more human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cal Newport&#39;s &#34;Deep Life Stack&#34; - Layer 1: Discipline</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/cal-newports-deep-life-stack-layer-1-discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/cal-newports-deep-life-stack-layer-1-discipline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last post I introduced Cal Newport&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Deep Life Stack&amp;rdquo;, his program to put your life on a more solid foundation. Today I want to expand on this and have a look at the fist layer, &amp;ldquo;discipline&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we want to start some meaningful changes in our lives, the first step, according to Cal, is to change our peception of ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our thinking and our behaviour are deeply linked together. If I am well organised, have everything under control and can stay calm even when faced with difficult situations, I also have the mental image of being well organised with a decent amount of self-discipline. But if I have been living my life without much of a plan and maybe have a few skeletons in the closet, like unfinished projects, or 20 failed attempts at dieting, or attempting to overhaul my life again and again without success, then the mental image I have of myself is probably not the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s where the discipline layer can help. If (I&amp;rsquo;m exaggerating here) I think of myself as a loser who can&amp;rsquo;t get anything done anyway because that&amp;rsquo;s the way it has always been (doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if this is actually the case or if this is only in my mind), then it will be almost impossible for me to change because my attitude will be &amp;ldquo;I will fail anyway&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So first we have to change our image of ourselves. And since we can not really change our thoughts, the way to get there is to change our behaviour first, and the thoughts and our self-perception will follow. This is classic behavioural psychology and the same basic idea behavioural therapy is based on. Body and mind are one and influence each other, changes in behaviour are followed by changes in the mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what do we do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cal suggests creating three keystone habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exact nature of these three habits is less important, the goal is to convince yourself that you are able to set your mind on something and then follow through, even if it is not always easy or pleasant. In other words, you should start thinking of yourself as a disciplined person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The habits should therefore require a certain investment of time and energy, but they should still be managebale on a daily basis. If you want to improve your fitness, &amp;ldquo;I look at my dumbbells once a day&amp;rdquo; is probaly not enough, as it will hardly have any impact, but &amp;ldquo;I do a hardcore 90 minutes Crossfit workout every day&amp;rdquo; is way too much, you will not be able to keep this up for long. It should be something in between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, the habits are spread across different areas of your life, for example one habit could be about health/spirituality, one about work/profession and one about your hobbies/personal development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After thinking about this for a while (in other words, totally overthinking it), I&amp;rsquo;ve settled on these three keystone habits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing&lt;/strong&gt;: I want to spend at least 15 minutes every day writing something. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what or how, it can be on a computer, can be on paper, can be a journal entry, a blog article, a short story&amp;hellip; whatever. Just write.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yoga/Meditation&lt;/strong&gt;: I want to spend 20 minutes every day practicing meditation or doing a small yoga session, therefore doing something for my mental and physical health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cleaning my apartment&lt;/strong&gt;: I will set aside some time each day (doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how much or how little) to clean and tidy up my place, because my surroundings have a huge impact on how I&amp;rsquo;m feeling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to to track these habits, I just downloaded a habit tracker template from some random website and printed it out so that I can record and check off every day that I have my habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now let&amp;rsquo;s do this for a few weeks, and then we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the next layer, where we&amp;rsquo;ll look at our values and bring them up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post 005/100 of the 100DaysToOffload Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a translation of the original German post made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; and then manually adapted to (hopefully) sound a bit more human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cal Newport&#39;s &#34; Deep Life Stack&#34;: 4 Months to reinvent your life </title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/cal-newports-deep-life-stack-4-months-to-reinvent-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/cal-newports-deep-life-stack-4-months-to-reinvent-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I usually stay away from the &amp;ldquo;productivity&amp;rdquo; genre on YouTube as far as possible, because there are just too many influencers on there who boast about how great they are at being productive, how super sophisticated their productivity system or bullet journal is, or who produce these quite frankly ridiculous &amp;ldquo;study with me for 13 hours&amp;rdquo; videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very pleasant exception to this is Cal Newport&amp;rsquo;s podcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calnewport.com/&#34;&gt;Cal Newport&lt;/a&gt; has been blogging about productivity since around 2007, has by now published 7 books (including &amp;ldquo;Deep Work&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Digital Minimalism&amp;rdquo;), has been running a weekly podcast for a few years now (early on he posted several times a week) and regularly publishes long form articles in magazines such as &amp;ldquo;The New Yorker&amp;rdquo;. And these are all just things he does on the side; his day job is being a professor of computer science at Georgetown University in Washington DC. So I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s wrong to assume he knows a thing or two about productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and he&amp;rsquo;s also my exact age, which may or may not trigger a bit of anxiety and feeling of inadequacy in me&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, his approach is not &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to get a new bullet journal&amp;rdquo;, but more general and holistic, he&amp;rsquo;s all about how to set up your life in such a way that you get the things you want to do done and still have free time and energy left so you&amp;rsquo;re not constantly stressed out of your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I like a lot about his podcast is that he often presents ideas that are still in the making and then picks them up again in later episodes and develops them further. In one of his latest &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0G7Wu4DnDaw&#34;&gt;podcast episodes&lt;/a&gt; he presented a 4-month plan to put your life on a new, hopefully more stable ground. This is based on an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G-6ua6UCeGM&#34;&gt;earlier idea&lt;/a&gt; that he continues to develop and refine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He suggests to divide the procedure into four successive layers which he calls the &amp;ldquo;deep life stack&amp;rdquo;. Here it is as a picture, with an explanation afterwards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;https://82mhz.net/images/CalNewport4MonthsEN.svg&#34; height=&#34;400x&#34; alt=&#34;4 layers, discipline, values, control, vision&#34;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four layers that build on each other are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discipline as the lowest layer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Values as the second&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control as the third&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vision as the highest and last&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give just a very rough summary, the individual layers are about the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discipline: Develop an image of yourself as a disciplined person&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Values: Reflect on and clearly define your own values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control: Take control over recurring tasks, automate or eliminate where possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vision: Develop a plan for how yout life should develop in the next X months/years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to discuss the individual levels, how Cal defines them and my thoughts on them in more detail in later posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach makes a lot of sense to me, and since I am currently thinking a lot about where I want my life to be headed, I think this a good way for me to deal with it in a more structured manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cal suggests to set apart two weeks for the first layer (discipline), 4 weeks for the next two and 6 weeks for the last (vision). That makes the whole process last about four months. He recommends starting at the beginning of September, because then you end up exactly at the end of December after four months and start the new year with a structured plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m starting this week, in mid-September instead of early September, but that&amp;rsquo;s okay. I&amp;rsquo;m off work for three weeks now and so I have enough time to start thinking about this, and also my birthday is coming up, which is generally a good time to reflect on my life and plan where to go next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post 004/100 of the 100DaysToOffload Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a translation of the original German post made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; and then manually adapted to (hopefully) sound a bit more human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books I read in August 2023</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/books-i-read-in-august-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/books-i-read-in-august-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first post of what I hope will be a monthly series in which I take a look back at the books I read the past month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really reach my goal of one book a week, which was partly due to the fact that I started some books and put them down again after two or three days, because I realised that they just weren&amp;rsquo;t right for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I managed to read three books, which I want to briefly summarise here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;atwood&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Margaret Atwood&lt;/em&gt;: The Handmaids Tale&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw this book somewhere online on a list of the best sci-fi novels of the 80s when I was looking for new reading material, and since the title looked vaguely familiar (there is an adaptation of the material as a TV series, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen it), I decided to give it a read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily call the book science fiction though, it&amp;rsquo;s more of an alternate reality, what-if scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, what if the radical evangelical Christians rose to power in the US and turned the country into a theocracy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outcome is pretty much what you&amp;rsquo;d expect: A Christian version of the current Islamic theocracies, coupled with the cold inhumane atmosphere of Catholic schools and orphanages of (hopefully) days gone by, and with a bit of Nazi Germany sprinkled on top. Women have no rights, have to be subservient to men at all times and are pretty much only there to have children (if they can, because many people became sterile in the preceding war, especially the men). The men are in charge, and anyone who is even remotely suspected of not being completely in line with the ideology is hanged or shot on sight. Love thy neighbour, you know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main character is the maid Offred, who is one of the few remaining fertile women and therefore lives in the house of the Commander and his wife Serena Joy, where she is subjected once a month to a bizarre impregnation ritual by the Commander and his wife and treated like dirt the rest of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book starts on a random day in Offred&amp;rsquo;s life with Offred just talking about her everyday life, and so a picture of the world she lives in, how it came about, and what kind of life she had before only emerges very slowly. This makes it a bit hard at first to get into the story, but once you&amp;rsquo;re in, you can&amp;rsquo;t put the book down and just shiver again and again at how strange and insane and yet absolutely within the realm of possibility the world described here is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;woz&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steve Wozniak&lt;/em&gt;: iWoz&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this book, I had the weird feeling that I might have read it before, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really remember much, so I just read it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Wozniak is the co-founder of Apple (together with the other, more famous Steve) and the one who designed the first Apple computers completely by himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this autobiography he goes over his life, from his childhood, where his father, also an engineer, introduced him to the world of electronics, to his first computer designs, to his first real job at HP, his first encounter with Steve Jobs, the founding of Apple Computers and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely exciting to read and you get a good look into the history of the micro computer from a very unique perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But. The book reads as if he just spent a few hours recording everything he could think of into a voice recording app and then someone typed it all up, put it in the right order and called it a book. His style of speaking is very redundant and verbose (not to say rambling), and a little more care in editing to make it more concise and to the point would have helped the reading flow a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;goldberg&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Natalie Goldberg&lt;/em&gt;: Writing down the Bones&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If The Internet&lt;sup&gt;TM&lt;/sup&gt; is to be believed, &amp;ldquo;Writing down the Bones&amp;rdquo; or as it is called in German &amp;ldquo;writing in cafés&amp;rdquo; (why translate a title when you can just make up a completely different one?) is one of THE books about creative writing, and what better reading is there at the beginning of a blogging challenge than such a book?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I went for it and was not disappointed! The book is divided into many small, unconnected chapters, each of which is self-contained and they cover a range of topics, from philosophical reflections about writing to concrete tips or simply observations of the author about herself and her relationship to writing. So you can just pick it up again and again and look through it and read a chapter or two for inspiration, whatever you feel like in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highly recommended, The Internet didn&amp;rsquo;t promise too much! I think if I come across a cheap copy of the book (I borrowed it from the library), I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely get it just to have it on the table and flip through it every now and then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post 003/100 of the 100DaysToOffload Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a translation of the original German post made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; and then manually adapted to (hopefully) sound a bit more human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogroll or &#34;I want one too!&#34;</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/blogroll-or-i-want-one-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/blogroll-or-i-want-one-too/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by Noisy Deadline&amp;rsquo;s post &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://noisydeadlines.net/blog-update-bringing-back-the-blogroll&#34;&gt;Bringing back the Blogroll&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; and by the blogrolls I&amp;rsquo;ve already seen on some other sites, I wanted to set one up for myself too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the concept of a blogroll, which as far as I understand is a list of blogs I like and follow (which I already have on my links page), but I thought I could do one better and create a list of all the latest posts from these blogs as well, ordered by date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first saw this concept on &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.mozz.us/gopher/i-logout.cz/1/bongusta&#34;&gt;Bongusta!&lt;/a&gt;, which is a gopher phlog aggregator, and matto has the same thing on his &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.mozz.us/gopher/box.matto.nl/1/phlogroll&#34;&gt;gophersite&lt;/a&gt; as well, so I stole the idea from them (without feeling even a trace of guilt or remorse!) and created my own version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some failed attempts, I decided to use the tool &lt;strong&gt;sfeed&lt;/strong&gt;, which fetches the latest posts from a list of rss feeds and writes them to a tab-delimited text file for each feed. There is also an option to output the list of new posts directly as html, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like the formatting, I really wanted to sort according to the latest posts of all feeds sorted by date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I built my own parser in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this sounds like &amp;ldquo;just quickly whipped something up&amp;rdquo;, but since I&amp;rsquo;m not a Python expert and had to google every single command, it took me a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now it works, sfeed fetches the latest articles from a list of RSS feeds, my Python script parses them out as Markdown in the right format and Hugo then integrates it into the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result can be admired &lt;a href=&#34;../../../../blogroll&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and can be accessed via the menu option &amp;ldquo;links&amp;rdquo;. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll add a separate menu entry, I&amp;rsquo;m not quite sure yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, I&amp;rsquo;m happy with it for now. So far I&amp;rsquo;m still updating manually, so the list might be a few days behind. If I find the time and feel like it, I&amp;rsquo;ll switch to automated updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post 002/100 of the 100DaysToOffload-Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a translation of the original German post made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; and then manually adapted to (hopefully) sound a bit more human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Days to offload</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/100-days-to-offload/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/09/100-days-to-offload/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes there are things that you read or just see somewhere and you immediately think &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rsquo;s cool, I&amp;rsquo;ll do that&amp;rdquo;. Some time ago I came across the &lt;a href=&#34;https://100daystooffload.com/&#34;&gt;100 Days to offload&lt;/a&gt; challenge, and this was one of those things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge is to write 100 blogposts within one year. Of course, I mentioned it right away on Mastodon that I was doing the challenge, so now I have the self-imposed task of writing 100 blogposts within one year, i.e. from today until the end of August 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are simple, to quote from the website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some simple and reasonable guidelines if you want to take part in #100DaysToOffload:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This needs to be done on a personal blog, not a corporate blog. If you don’t have a personal blog, you can sign up for a free one at &lt;a href=&#34;https://bearblog.dev&#34;&gt;Bear Blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no specific start date. Your 100 posts can start or end whenever you want them to, they just need to be completed within 365 days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish 100 new posts in the space of a year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are no limits to what you can post about – write about whatever interests you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you have published an article, don’t forget to post a link on your social media with the hashtag &lt;code&gt;#100DaysToOffload&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get your friends involved!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What topics should I write about? No idea! Whatever comes to mind, probably a lot of stuff about tech, tutorials, some hobby projects I&amp;rsquo;m doing, rants about cars and lousy city design&amp;hellip; I think there are enough things to get off my chest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I posted on Mastodon that I&amp;rsquo;m doing the challenge and was looking for fellow participants, a few people actually came forward, so here are some of my fellow participants in random order &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dustin also wants to start today (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.spotek.io/@dustin&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://0xdstn.site/&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screwtape as well (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.sdf.org/@screwtape&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gopher.tildeverse.org/tilde.club/1/~screwtape/synthember-100days-tooffload/&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matto (&lt;a href=&#34;https://pub.matto.nl/u/matto&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://box.matto.nl/&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.mozz.us/gopher/box.matto.nl/&#34;&gt;Phlog&lt;/a&gt;) and Prahou (&lt;a href=&#34;https://merveilles.town/@prahou&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://triapul.cz/&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.mozz.us/gopher/triapul.cz/&#34;&gt;Phlog&lt;/a&gt;) have already started last month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And Noisy Deadlines (&lt;a href=&#34;https://writing.exchange/@noisydeadlines&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://noisydeadlines.net/&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;) thought, one year is way too long, I can do it in 1/3 of the time!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might now be wondering, what the &amp;hellip; is a phlog?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, some people have normal http websites, but there are also the purists who use text-based protocols, either &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gopher&#34;&gt;Gopher&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gemini_(protocol)&#34;&gt;Gemini&lt;/a&gt;, and depending on the protocol, the pages are then called blogs (http), phlogs (gopher) or gemlogs (gemini). What do you know! I had no idea&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll limit myself to this website here for now, but maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll add a gopher or gemini site in the future, we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now to complete the confusion about all the outdated retro protocols:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matto has set up a channel on IRC at &lt;a href=&#34;ircs://irc.libera.chat:6697&#34;&gt;libera.chat&lt;/a&gt; called #phloggersgarage, where a nice little community around blogging (phlogging&amp;hellip;) is already slowly developing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s going to be exciting, interesting, challenging and I&amp;rsquo;m sure also frustrating at times over the next few months, but that&amp;rsquo;s all part of a challenge, otherwise it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a translation of the original German post made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; and then manually adapted to (hopefully) sound a bit more human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I post the gopher pages here via http proxy. I hope the purists will forgive me, but this is the way I access the pages so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to leave the comfort of my web browser&amp;hellip;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Design Part 2</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/08/updated-design-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/08/updated-design-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know it: You only want to change a minor thing on the theme of the website, but you can&amp;rsquo;t seem to get it right and in the end escalate completely and rewrite the whole website from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;back-story&#34;&gt;Back story:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website was created with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and originally had the theme &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/themes/hugo-papermod/&#34;&gt;Papermod&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, then &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/themes/hugo-blog-awesome/&#34;&gt;Hugo Blog Awesome&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; and finally &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/themes/hugo-theme-console/&#34;&gt;Console&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really happy with any of these themes, so I had already modified the Console theme quite a bit to be more like what I wanted it to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, some things in the CSS were quite weirdly implemented, and no matter what I tried, some things just didn&amp;rsquo;t work out the way I wanted them to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;and-now&#34;&gt;And now:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometime during the past week I had enough and just started to rewrite the whole site from scratch. The structure of course stays as it was before, but without all the things in the code I don&amp;rsquo;t need anyway and with a CSS that does exactly what (and only what!) I want. And with a little help from a good friend, who happens to be a web designer, I think I did a pretty good job!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things are still a bit rough and in need of improvement of course, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure there will be the occasional change here and there, but I think for now I have the site the way I like it and the way I imagined it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now the blogging can really start. More about that at the end of next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and a big sorry to those who have subscribed to my RSS feed, I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I&amp;rsquo;ve caused a bit of a mess there. I hope the time of big changes is over now and the site can stay the way it is for some time to come!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a translation of the original German post made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; and then manually adapted to (hopefully) sound a bit more human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website update with new sections</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/08/website-update-with-new-sections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/08/website-update-with-new-sections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a little announcement today, I have added two new sections to the website: Links and Bookclub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links should be pretty self-explanatory, on this page I collect links to interesting blogs, articles, documents&amp;hellip;. everything I find interesting or worth knowing and want to share or remember for later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under bookclub I collect the list of books I&amp;rsquo;ve read, maybe a book review here and there and generally everything that somehow has to do with books and reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mainly read either SciFi or non-fiction about psychology, society, technology and everything in between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggestions and recommendations for good books that don&amp;rsquo;t yet appear here are always welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Design and now also in German</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/08/new-design-and-now-also-in-german/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/08/new-design-and-now-also-in-german/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The site is barely two months old and already the first redesign is coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t really warm up to the old theme, but luckily Hugo makes it really easy to change the theme. Of course, you&amp;rsquo;re still going to spend days tinkering to get everything exactly the way you want it, and it&amp;rsquo;s still not exactly the way &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; want it, but that will come in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the site is now based on a modified &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrmierzejewski/hugo-theme-console&#34;&gt;Hugo Console Theme&lt;/a&gt; and, big news, it&amp;rsquo;s bilingual!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo makes it incredibly easy to create a bilingual site and switch back and forth between languages. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t a thing I was even considering when I decided to use Hugo, but it&amp;rsquo;s a happy coincidence now after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan is to write the posts in German, because I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt a bit weird writing everything in English (a foreign language for me) and then translating the German posts into English with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe go over it again so that it sounds like me and not like an AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see how I get on with it. I won&amp;rsquo;t translate the older posts into German for now, but I think we can live with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a translation of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://82mhz.net/de/posts/redesign&#34;&gt;original German post&lt;/a&gt; made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepl.com/&#34;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; and then manually adapted to (hopefully) sound a bit more human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge 2023 - Epilogue</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/08/old-computer-challenge-2023-epilogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/08/old-computer-challenge-2023-epilogue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So the OCC 2023 ended almost three weeks ago and everyone went back to the year 2023 and to using their modern computers. At least I did. But let&amp;rsquo;s explore what remaind for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to take a moment to look back and examine what was good, which tools and workflows stuck with me and what is better left back on the old computer (which was really just a VM in my case).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-good&#34;&gt;The Good&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On both my Desktop and Laptop Computers I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href=&#34;https://endeavouros.com&#34;&gt;Endeavouros&lt;/a&gt;, which is pretty much a preconfigured and nice looking Arch Linux with a few extras here and there. And because I am already familiar with it, I decided to just use this as the basis for my OCC computer as well, though with a much slimmer graphical interface (no KDE, just a &lt;a href=&#34;https://herbstluftwm.org/&#34;&gt;minimal tiling window manager&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main things I do on my private computer on a daily basis are communicating with friends, browse the web, watch videos on Youtube, listen to music, do some occasional coding and try my best not to spend too much time on social media (these days mostly Mastodon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lived (out of necessity of course) much more in the terminal than I usually do. I still, unfortunately communicate with friends and family via WhatsApp a lot, which I normally have open in a browser window because I hate typing on a touchscreen (if any manufacturer wants to bring back haptic keys with T9 support, I&amp;rsquo;m ready!). Like pretty much everything related to the modern web, this was more an exercise in frustration than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since just opening a browser window filled up about half my RAM before I even opened a single website, having a bunch of tabs open at all times and flipping between them quickly turned out to be impossible. So I needed to find ways to use WhatsApp, IRC, Mastodon, Youtube, VS Code, Obsidian and a few other programs and services on a computer with limited resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;rsquo;s a surprising number of very lightweight terminal apps around for pretty much every usecase, I was surprised!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ones that stuck with me were&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/d99kris/nchat&#34;&gt;nchat&lt;/a&gt; for Whatsapp, which has a very nice ncurses interface and works beautifully (remember to install the font &lt;a href=&#34;https://fonts.google.com/noto/specimen/Noto+Emoji&#34;&gt;noto-fonts-emoji&lt;/a&gt; if you want to see emojis instead of unicode placeholders)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/RasmusLindroth/tut&#34;&gt;tut&lt;/a&gt; for Mastodon, same thing, beautiful ncurses interface, works like a charm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lynx.invisible-island.net&#34;&gt;lynx&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://links.twibright.com&#34;&gt;links2&lt;/a&gt; for web browsing in the terminal (no problem on lightweight static websites, but horrible for modern webapps bloated with js etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://irssi.org&#34;&gt;irssi&lt;/a&gt; for IRC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rawtext.club/~sloum/bombadillo.html&#34;&gt;bombadillo&lt;/a&gt; for accessing gemini and gopher sites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And for coding, writing blog entries etc. I just used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vim.org/&#34;&gt;best terminal editor&lt;/a&gt; ever (once you learn how to use it, that is!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially I considered watching Youtube just impossible, but a few days into the OCC someone pointed me to &lt;a href=&#34;https://yewtu.be&#34;&gt;https://yewtu.be&lt;/a&gt;, where I could search for a video, get the URL, copy it to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yt-dlp/yt-dlp&#34;&gt;yt-dlp&lt;/a&gt; and just download the video in a resolution low enough to be watchable on my system. Neat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For listening to music I used my old iPod or just turned the radio on (yes, FM radio still exists! I was surprised, too).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of these apps I actually still keep using, like nchat, tut, bombadillo and irssi, because they&amp;rsquo;re just so lightweight and easily started with a few keystrokes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to say though, the most difficult thing about learning all these terminal apps was to memorize all the different key combinations! What&amp;rsquo;s just a click on the right button in a GUI turns into hunting around for which key combination does what you want to do, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that every single piece of software seems to invent its own shortcuts! Want to look at an attached media file? in tut it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;rsquo;m&amp;rsquo;, but in nchat it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;ctrl+v&amp;rsquo;. And it&amp;rsquo;s like that for everything&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s maddening! Once you&amp;rsquo;ve gotten used to it though, everything flies and is much simpler to use than clicking around in bloated graphical UIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So everything is great, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-bad&#34;&gt;The Bad&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short: The web. Just everything about it. I already mentioned that just firing up Firefox or Vivaldi (my browser of choice for most things) uses a good chunk of RAM, and opening pretty much any website quickly fills up the rest. My system was constantly swapping, which of course slows everything down even further, and I was really glad I had an SSD, otherwise I would have had to live with the sound of a constantly whirring mechanical harddrive in my ears while slowly going insane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using text based browsers is possible, but by far not all websites load or are usable, so you often have to switch to a gui based browser and suffer. And that&amp;rsquo;s with all adblockers turned to maximum and JS disabled where possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could write a whole article about this, and maybe one day I will, but the modern web is just becoming more and more awful to use with every passing year. We&amp;rsquo;re burning gigawatthours worth of energy and are producing tons and tons of CO2 in the process just to transmit ads and self playing videos and all kinds of other crap that &lt;strong&gt;nobody even wants&lt;/strong&gt; through the net! And for what? So big corporations can get richer and richer, while the rest of us are being stripped of our privacy and the global climate is going to hell along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s never been more apparent to me than in the last few weeks: The modern web (and by extension a lot of the rest of the modern world) is a mistake. We should just hit &lt;em&gt;reset&lt;/em&gt;, go back to 1995 or so and start over, and do it better. What we&amp;rsquo;re doing right now is clearly not sustainable, nor is it healthy (not for the environment and not for our minds).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I don&amp;rsquo;t want to end on this sour note, because there was also&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-great&#34;&gt;The Great&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community! Without a doubt, that was the best part of it! People were blogging about it, talking on Mastodon and IRC exchanging ideas and frustrations, giving each other support and tips&amp;hellip; it was great. &lt;strong&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong&gt; how being social online is supposed to work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So thank you Solene for coming up with the OCC, thank you to all the participants who shared their experiences and thank you to everyone who read my posts and helped me out where necessary!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to doing this again next year :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Days 6 and 7</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-days-6-and-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 07:29:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-days-6-and-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So the last two days of the Old Computer Challenge went by in the blink of an eye, and not a lot has happened, so I&amp;rsquo;m putting them together in one post. But I still wanted to note a few things down, and I might also a wrap-up some time next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;day-6&#34;&gt;Day 6&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was boiling hot outside (35°C) and I am just completely useless in these kinds of temperatures (in Germany we also don&amp;rsquo;t tend to have AC, so no way to cool my apartment down). So I was just lying around most of the day, trying to move as little as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in the evening it cooled down and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d explore the &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; site of the internet some more, this time in the form of looking at Bulletin Board Systems (BBS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now these are definitely a product and technology of the 80s, and I am too young to have experienced them in their time (in the 80s I was busy learning to walk, talk and digest solid food), so I don&amp;rsquo;t have any nostalgia for them, but some are still around and some are around again, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d have a look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first thought was, I want the authentic experience, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try it on real hardware! I still have my dads old C64 here, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have a modem for it, so that idea was scrapped immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, how about BMC64 on a Raspberry Pi? I tried it before and it felt like a pretty authentic C64 experience (esp. on a Raspi 400), but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have network drivers, so no luck there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C64 mini maybe? But again, it can&amp;rsquo;t access the net. Next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raspberry Pi with an emulator? I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like going thorugh the trouble of downloading an image and setting everything up, so nope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, Vice emulator on my PC. Here I cheated because I used my regular computer, not the slow one, because running emulation on it might have been too much to ask of it. But after downloading the emulator and googling around for a suitable terminal software I realized that the process of getting it running might be a bit more involved than I anticipated, and I really didn&amp;rsquo;t have the patience, so I abandoned that too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So eventually I settled on downloading syncterm, which can emulate all kinds of old terminals, including the C64s, and finally I could google the addresses of some BBSs and see what it was like back 40 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I realized pretty quickly that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t my cup of tea. While it was interesting to see how much love went into some of these boards, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t really get into them. Maybe on authentic hardware and an old CRT it will be a better experience, but looking at huge ugly fonts on a modern laptop display just didn&amp;rsquo;t feel good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BBC from The Old Net even has the capability to open modern websites on it, so I tried a few, but again, the font is huge and ugly and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy to read&amp;hellip; I think for me this is missing the nostalgia factor that makes the experience special. But without the rose-tinted glasses on it felt a bit too old-school for my taste. My nostalgia for C64 and Amiga lies in the games, and my experiences with the online world began towards the end of the 90s, so that&amp;rsquo;s what feels nostalgic for me and what I enjoy revisiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, it was an interesting experience and I learned something in the process, if only about myself ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;day-7&#34;&gt;Day 7&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this day is even shorter to wrap up, because I was at a family gathering all day and didn&amp;rsquo;t use my computer much at all. I only had my phone with my and did my best to stick to my rules of only using it for communication, but I may have accidentally opened the browser once or twice&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with that the Old Computer Challenge is coming to an end!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was fun, frustrating and enlightening at various times! The best thing was by far the community on the fediverse, IRC and reading all the blog entries and experiences of the other participants! I can&amp;rsquo;t wait what @solene has in store for us next year and I will definitely participate again and try to keep in touch with some of the people I met along the way. And for that alone the experience was worth it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will summarize my thoughts in a few days, so there will be one more post, but for now I&amp;rsquo;m relieved to have a computer that feels fast again to work with ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Day 5: Youtube Videos on an iPod Classic</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-5-youtube-videos-on-an-ipod-classic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 15:11:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-5-youtube-videos-on-an-ipod-classic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;note&#34;&gt;Note&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only semi-related to the OldComputerChallenge, but I revisited the idea of downloading videos from Youtube and putting them on an old iPod. I had already figured out the commands a while ago, but I had to refresh my memory from my bash history and because I figure this might actually be of interest to some people, I wrote it as a tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, this is about downloading videos from Youtube and putting them on the iPod, not about accessing Youtube straight from the iPod. That&amp;rsquo;s not possible because iPods (apart from the iPod touch, which is basically an iPhone) don&amp;rsquo;t have wifi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while ago I got into old iPods (of course like so many people thanks to a certain &lt;a href=&#34;https://yewtu.be/channel/UC7Jwj9fkrf1adN4fMmTkpug&#34;&gt;easily excitable australian youtuber&lt;/a&gt;) and got myself an old iPod Classic with a 160GB harddisk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember thinking back then that they looked really amazing and that 160GB was just a phenomenal amount of storage, enough for my entire music collection at the time, but of course being a university student who was just barely getting by financially there was no way I could afford one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a decade and a half later, thankfully I have an income now and old iPods have come down in price as well (double win!), so the time had come to get one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://82mhz.net/iPodClassic.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;iPodClassic&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course the first thing I did was to put &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rockbox.org&#34;&gt;Rockbox&lt;/a&gt; on it, and here it is running the fantastic &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/D0-0K/adwaitapod&#34;&gt;Adawaitapod&lt;/a&gt; theme by &lt;a href=&#34;https://d00k.net/&#34;&gt;D00k&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So then putting music and podcasts and audiobooks on it is pretty straightforward, just copy your MP3s, OGGs, FLACs etc. over and you&amp;rsquo;re good to go! No iTunes, no messing around trying to get libgtkpod working, it just works like any other MP3-Player, you mount it as a USB-storage device on your computer, copy the files over and that&amp;rsquo;s it. The way it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, this thing can play videos too, right? Could it be possible to rip videos from youtube and put them on the iPod so I can strain my eyes watching them on a way too tiny screen like it&amp;rsquo;s 2005?&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course it is, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have wasted your time with this introduction if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;necessary-software&#34;&gt;Necessary software&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need two pieces of software:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yt-dlp/yt-dlp&#34;&gt;yt-dlp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ffmpeg.org/&#34;&gt;ffmpeg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where to get them and how to install them depends on your OS and distro of choice of course, so I&amp;rsquo;m not going to write up a tutorial about that, I&amp;rsquo;m going to assume you can figure it out and have it installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ripping-the-videos-from-youtube-with-yt-dlp&#34;&gt;Ripping the video(s) from Youtube with yt-dlp&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, get the URL of the youtube-video you would like to rip. Just open the video in your browser and copy it from your browsers address bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, run yt-dlp with the URL as parameter, and I like to tell it to rip the 480p version of the video to save bandwidth. We need to make the video even smaller for the iPod, so there is no point in downloading the full 1080p or 4k file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ yt-dlp -S &amp;#34;res:480&amp;#34; &amp;#39;https://www.youtube.com/XXXXX&amp;#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note the quotation marks (&amp;rsquo;), they are necessary in case the youtube link contains characters that the shell would interpret as special characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works on playlists too btw! Just get the URL of the playlist instead and run yt-dlp like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ yt-dlp -S &amp;#34;res:480&amp;#34; --yes-playlist &amp;#39;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XXXXX&amp;#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now we will most likely end up with a video (or videos) in the &lt;em&gt;webm&lt;/em&gt; file format. That&amp;rsquo;s nice, but way too modern and high-res for our tiny little iPod. So let&amp;rsquo;s make it smaller and crappier!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;converting-for-the-ipod-with-ffmpeg&#34;&gt;Converting for the iPod with ffmpeg&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here we come across an unfortunate issue. The iPod is modern enough to be able to decode h.264 videos in hardware, but Rockbox has no support for it and can only decode the older (and worse) mpeg2 standard. What this means in practice is that we need to convert the videos to mpeg2 which creates bigger files than h.264 at a comparable quality or worse looking video at the same filesize. Quality is of less concern in my opinion, because the iPods screen is tiny and a few compression artefacts here and there only add to the retro experience, but filesize might be important if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of space available on the iPod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, we now need to fire up ffmpeg to convert the video to a format the iPod (and Rockbox) understands. The command is pretty straightforward, the for loop is only necessary if you have downloaded multiple videos, but it also works if you have only one video, so I only ever use this line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ for i in *.webm; do ffmpeg -i &amp;#34;$i&amp;#34; -c:v mpeg2video -b:v 4000k -acodec libmp3lame -ab 192k -vf scale=320:-1 &amp;#34;${i%.*}.mpg&amp;#34;; done
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to change the filesize (and quality), you can play around with the video bitrate (the number after -b:v) and the audio bitrate (the number after -ab) until you have the right values dialed in for your usecase. The bitrates above work well for me, so I&amp;rsquo;m happy with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if everything went well, you have a bunch of video files in your folder with the extension *&lt;em&gt;mpg&lt;/em&gt;, and you can just copy them over to your iPod, open them in Rockbox like any other file and enjoy your favorite 80s music videos on the go! (I know that&amp;rsquo;s what you came here for ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://82mhz.net/iPodClassicMJ.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;iPodClassic&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(It looks better in person btw., my camera is not the greatest. But the iPods screen is actually pretty nice for its age!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bonus-round-converting-to-h264-for-the-original-ipod-software&#34;&gt;Bonus round: Converting to h.264 for the original iPod software&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I mentioned, the iPod is capable of playing h.264 videos, so if you&amp;rsquo;re still rocking the original Apple software, you can also convert you videos to a higher quality (and smaller filesize) codec like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt; for i in *.webm; do ffmpeg -i &amp;#34;$i&amp;#34; -f mp4 -vcodec mpeg4 -vf scale=-2:320 -maxrate 1536k -b:v 768k -qmin 3 -qmax 5 -bufsize 4096k -g 300 -c:a aac -b:a 192k -ar 44100 -ac 2 &amp;#34;${i%.*}.mp4&amp;#34;; done
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPod Classic which I have came out in 2007 but the first iPod to allow video playback, the iPod Video, was released in 2005. They are technically very similar and have the same screen.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Day 4</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 08:50:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to take this post to get out some thoughts about the internet, social media and mental health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is this related to the OldComputerChallenge?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the longest time now I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a facebook profile, and I never had a twitter profile or a tiktok account or a profile on any of the new social media platforms that are en vogue these days. The only social media I had left was Instagram, but I stopped using it a few months ago because I realized I was just mindlessly scrolling through posts for hours on end without getting much value or enjoyment out of it at all. Which is exactly what the platform wants me to do of course, but it&amp;rsquo;s also the exact opposite of what &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; want to do. So I ditched it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I was better off for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But because I still keep an eye out on what&amp;rsquo;s new and exciting in internetland (Neuland, as our head of state famously called it a few years ago), I was intrigued by mastodon and the fediverse and the idea of having my own blog and not being at the mercy of an eccentric billionaire who could turn my profile off at any moment with no way for me to ever get it back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I got an account on mastodon. And started following a few people, and a few hashtags, and discovered the OldComputerChallenge. And that there was a whole community of people hosting their own blogs on simple webservers, using gopher or gemini, chatting on IRC and basically using the internet like it was 1999 (or so). So that intrigued me, and I decided to do the OldComputerChallenge as well, and blog about it and be in touch with the other participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then something interesting happened. The first few days I tried to keep up with all the blogs, keep up with IRC, follow all the retrocomputing-related tags on mastodon, write my own posts and do all that while working in a slow OS with unfamiliar tools and workflows&amp;hellip; and I got stressed. A lot. I tried to do too many things, keep up with too many posts, flip back and forth between different tools and programs and communication channels, write my own stuff and do it all at the same time. Bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me two days to realize that this is really stressful, unhealthy and (most embarrassing to admit) completely unnecessary. Nobody cares if I don&amp;rsquo;t show up on IRC. Nobody cares if I read their post a day later, or not at all because I missed it. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to be omnipresent and get all the information as quickly as possible, read all the articles, follow all the hashtags, answer all the posts etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to disconnect. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to only show up on IRC occasionally. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to only scroll through mastodon once or twice a day. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to not read people&amp;rsquo;s posts if I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or the energy. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to miss out on some conversations, posts, articles, videos, podcasts and whatever else is out there. And it&amp;rsquo;s also okay to post my own stuff not when I think I have to, but when it&amp;rsquo;s ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s ironic that by slowing down my computer I sped up my brain to the point where it wasn&amp;rsquo;t good for me anymore, before I realized that the slow approach also works (and works well) in other areas of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, of course I went through this cycle many, many times before, and the solution is always the same: notice it, take a deep breath, then change it. But occasionally a reminder to slow down and take a step back is needed, and this challenge certainly served as one :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 13:50:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On this day I was sick, so not a lot has happened, but I would like to still briefly share a few thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m spending far less time aimlessly surfing the web or watching youtube-videos for hours on end, simply because it&amp;rsquo;s not very much fun. Surfing works, but most sites are not very pleasant to look at or don&amp;rsquo;t work at all in a minimalist browser (think lynx, links2, luakit) or they slow the computer down to a crawl when using vivaldi (which is already slow thanks to its significant memory footprint). Important lesson: don&amp;rsquo;t have more than one or two tabs open at once. Just don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And watching youtube is pretty much impossible. Even just loading the start page takes forever, and trying to load a video&amp;hellip; just no. I had downloaded yt-dlp beforehand to be able to download yt-videos at a lower resolution, but I would still have to get the url from somewhere and honestly, I don&amp;rsquo;t even miss it. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll eventually catch up on a few interesting videos that I missed during the week, but right now I&amp;rsquo;m completely fine without spending the evening on my couch aimlessly browsing youtube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A win in my opinion!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For fun I fired up a VM (one core slowed down, 512mb RAM of course) with Windows XP and browsed some old sites via &lt;a href=&#34;https://theoldnet.com&#34;&gt;the old net&lt;/a&gt; using Retrozilla, and that turned out to be a surprising amount of fun! Retrozilla is also able to access gopher sites, and since most of the OCC-participants who run blogs keep them very minimal, starting at &lt;a href=&#34;https://occ.deadnet.se&#34;&gt;occ.deadnet.se&lt;/a&gt; and looking through the blog entries listed there was no problem at all. And &lt;strong&gt;way&lt;/strong&gt; faster than doing the same thing on a modern linux, despite a minimalist window manager and a lightweight browser (Midori). I even managed to install an old version of mIRC and join #oldcomputerchallenge on libera.chat, which was very surprising but pretty awesome and gave me a huge nostalgia hit :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putty still works on XP as well, so I can ssh into my &amp;ldquo;server&amp;rdquo; (a raspberry pi really) and do linux-y stuff on there. All in all a surprisingly nice and nostalgic experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I also switched my window manager from i3 to herbstluftwm. Why? First, I had already used herbstluftwm before and am familiar with how it works, and second, I like the name :) (for the non-German speaking world, &amp;ldquo;Herbstluft&amp;rdquo; means &amp;ldquo;autumn air&amp;rdquo;, which I think is just beautiful. Once I figure out how to post audio on here, I&amp;rsquo;ll put a file online with the correct pronounciation ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 18:00:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 2 is coming to a close. Today I was at work all day and so didn&amp;rsquo;t spend a whole lot of time on my slow computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, A thought occurred to me recently, because since I subscribed to mastodon a couple of weeks ago and especially since I started following some retro computing related postings (where I discoved the OCC in the first place), I discovered that there&amp;rsquo;s a thing called&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://communitywiki.org/static/SmolNet.html&#34;&gt;The SmolNet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is it? Well, according to the link above&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “smol” net is the “small” net. It’s small because it is build for friends and friends of friends. It doesn’t have to scale to millions of people because those millions should build their own local small nets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this help explaining it? No?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, if you&amp;rsquo;re in or approaching middle age right now, you probably remember the internet of the 90s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re too young for that, this might sound like grandpa telling stories about the war, but there was a time when the internet was young and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t yet entirely run by a handful of gigantic evil megacorporations (Amazon, Google, Facebook&amp;hellip;). Back then, people used to meet and chat on forums or IRC or BBSes (bulletin boards, but that was even before my time), and they would code their own personal websites and build communities and exchange their thoughts and ideas in this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came the web 2.0 with Facebook, Twitter, Youtube, Instagram etc., which opened the web up to the masses, but it also ushered in an era where everyone was on the same few platforms and where everyone&amp;rsquo;s profile looks like everyone elses because that was what the platform dictated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then &lt;strong&gt;The Algorithm&lt;/strong&gt; was introduced and turned the internet into a miserable and dystopian hellscape filled with online bullying and hatred and outrage because that&amp;rsquo;s what gets peoples attention and is good for the bank accounts of the Zuckerbergs and Dorseys and Musks of the world, but bad for essentially the rest of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s where we&amp;rsquo;re still at today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In between the cracks of this modern, corporatized, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pluralistic.net/2023/01/21/potemkin-ai/#hey-guys&#34;&gt;enshittified&lt;/a&gt; internet where everything looks the same and everyone is out to get your data and track you and bombard you with ads there is a small world where the internet of old still (or again?) exists. Where people build small websites, talk on IRC or BBSes, and use old protocols like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gopher_(protocol)&#34;&gt;gopher&lt;/a&gt; (or modernized versions like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gemini_(protocol)&#34;&gt;gemini&lt;/a&gt;) and exchange information in this way, far away from the walled gardens of Facebook, Twitter and such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like it was when the internet was new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet of old is still alive today. You just have to look in the right places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I think this is beautiful, and it makes me happy, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I discovered it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s explore it some more on day 3 :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 09:46:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, Day 1 is almost over, what have we learned?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern software sucks!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really, a lot of it is quite beautiful and easy to use, but boy, everything consumes so many resources! Just starting up a web browser (firefox or chrome doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter) takes a good ten seconds or more, and then we haven&amp;rsquo;t even loaded a single page yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And webpages are also so slow and bloated these days! I haven&amp;rsquo;t limited my bandwidth thankfully (otherwise I&amp;rsquo;d go completely crazy), but just trying to open any normal page I can watch the CPU hang at 100% load for 10, 20, 30 seconds even, and the memory consumption goes up and up and up&amp;hellip;. For comparison I installed Windows XP in a VM with the exact same settings as my modern linux (1 core, limited to 50%, 512mb RAM) and it runs! Installed retrozilla browser, and that is lightning fast as well (though not terribly useful any more because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t render modern sites very well&amp;hellip;. and let&amp;rsquo;s not even think about security). This just shows how much more resource-hungry everything has become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, sidenote: I noticed that this site here doesn&amp;rsquo;t render very well on old browsers either, and on links2 (console-based browser) it isn&amp;rsquo;t useable at all because the links to the posts are not accessible. Ups&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t know enough HTML to fix this though, so this is a problem for future me. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll have it sorted for the next OCC in a year ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About sites like YouTube&amp;hellip; yeah, best not to talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening to a podcast was fine though, I downloaded it through gpodder, copied it to my iPod and enjoyed it free of distraction on my couch :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plans for the upcoming days:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figure out more console based alternatives to the software I normally use (browser, podcatcher, mastodon-client, mail-client etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dive a bit more into Windows XP, if for nothing more than nostalgia&amp;rsquo;s sake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try not to go crazy with everything being so slow! :P&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Preparation</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 09:46:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-preparation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year I learned about &lt;a href=&#34;https://bsd.network/@solene&#34;&gt;Solene&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataswamp.org/~solene/2023-06-04-old-computer-challenge-v3.html&#34;&gt;Old Computer Challenge&lt;/a&gt;, and I thought hey, I might give it a go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this year the rules for the challenge are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s use a SLOW computer for 7 days. This will be achieved by various means with any hardware:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limit your computer&amp;rsquo;s CPU to use only 1 core. This can be set in the BIOS most of the time, and on Linux you can use &lt;code&gt;maxcores=1&lt;/code&gt; in the boot command line, on OpenBSD you can use &lt;code&gt;bsd.sp&lt;/code&gt; kernel for the duration of the challenge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limit your computer&amp;rsquo;s memory to 512 MB of memory (no swap limit). This can be set on Linux using the boot command line &lt;code&gt;mem=512MB&lt;/code&gt;. On OpenBSD, this can be achieved a bit similarly by using &lt;code&gt;datasize-max=512M&lt;/code&gt; in login.conf for your user&amp;rsquo;s login class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set your CPU frequency to the lowest minimum (which is pretty low on modern hardware!). On Linux, use the &amp;ldquo;powersave&amp;rdquo; frequency governor, in modern desktop environments the battery widget should offer an easy way to set the governor. On OpenBSD, run &lt;code&gt;apm -L&lt;/code&gt; (while apmd service is running). On Windows, in the power settings, set the frequency to minimum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, easy enough, right? Well, of course my natural tendency to overthink everything kicked in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I thought, I&amp;rsquo;d fire up my (almost) 20 year old laptop from back when I was in university. Turns out, the thing is really on its last legs, the battery has died long ago, the display hinges are barely holding together, the backlight (CFL, no LEDs) could give up at any moment&amp;hellip; not a pleasant experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://82mhz.net/aspire2001.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Acer Aspire 2001&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d just slow down my normal desktop PC to one core, 512mb RAM and limit the cpu frequency&amp;hellip; but that didn&amp;rsquo;t really feel old, it was just my normal computer a bit slower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after a lot of thinking what I ended up with is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep my desktop computer off for the week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use only my Laptop (a 2013 (or 2014?) 13 inch Macbook Air, almost old and vintage itself!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a VM in Virtualbox with 512mb RAM, one cpu core and limit the core to 50% speed (I have no idea how slow this actually is compared to a proper old computer, but it does feel slow, and that&amp;rsquo;s the point, right?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Endeavouros (an Arch Linux variant) with the i3 window manager and use mostly terminal apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For fun, I also installed a second VM (same specs as above) with Windows XP for that authentic retro-feeling (I used it back in the day before I switched to Linux in 2008 or so)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminate browsing and YouTube on my smartphone (because otherwise I would just use this all week) and only use the phone as a communication device, meaning only for SMS, WhatsApp, E-Mail and (shocker!) even as a proper telephone!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music comes from physical media, meaning CDs, vinyl, radio or an old iPod (yes, I&amp;rsquo;m lumping the iPod in with the physical media because it&amp;rsquo;s a dedicated device whose only purpose is to play music - and most importantly it can&amp;rsquo;t go online!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is the setup for now, we&amp;rsquo;ll see how the week goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://82mhz.net/oldComputerSetup.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Setup for the OldComputerChallenge&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the fun begin!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
