<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>windowsXP on 82MHz</title>
    <link>https://82mhz.net/tags/windowsxp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in windowsXP on 82MHz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 13:50:48 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://82mhz.net/tags/windowsxp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Old Computer Challenge - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 13:50:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/posts/2023/07/old-computer-challenge-day-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On this day I was sick, so not a lot has happened, but I would like to still briefly share a few thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m spending far less time aimlessly surfing the web or watching youtube-videos for hours on end, simply because it&amp;rsquo;s not very much fun. Surfing works, but most sites are not very pleasant to look at or don&amp;rsquo;t work at all in a minimalist browser (think lynx, links2, luakit) or they slow the computer down to a crawl when using vivaldi (which is already slow thanks to its significant memory footprint). Important lesson: don&amp;rsquo;t have more than one or two tabs open at once. Just don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And watching youtube is pretty much impossible. Even just loading the start page takes forever, and trying to load a video&amp;hellip; just no. I had downloaded yt-dlp beforehand to be able to download yt-videos at a lower resolution, but I would still have to get the url from somewhere and honestly, I don&amp;rsquo;t even miss it. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll eventually catch up on a few interesting videos that I missed during the week, but right now I&amp;rsquo;m completely fine without spending the evening on my couch aimlessly browsing youtube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A win in my opinion!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For fun I fired up a VM (one core slowed down, 512mb RAM of course) with Windows XP and browsed some old sites via &lt;a href=&#34;https://theoldnet.com&#34;&gt;the old net&lt;/a&gt; using Retrozilla, and that turned out to be a surprising amount of fun! Retrozilla is also able to access gopher sites, and since most of the OCC-participants who run blogs keep them very minimal, starting at &lt;a href=&#34;https://occ.deadnet.se&#34;&gt;occ.deadnet.se&lt;/a&gt; and looking through the blog entries listed there was no problem at all. And &lt;strong&gt;way&lt;/strong&gt; faster than doing the same thing on a modern linux, despite a minimalist window manager and a lightweight browser (Midori). I even managed to install an old version of mIRC and join #oldcomputerchallenge on libera.chat, which was very surprising but pretty awesome and gave me a huge nostalgia hit :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putty still works on XP as well, so I can ssh into my &amp;ldquo;server&amp;rdquo; (a raspberry pi really) and do linux-y stuff on there. All in all a surprisingly nice and nostalgic experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I also switched my window manager from i3 to herbstluftwm. Why? First, I had already used herbstluftwm before and am familiar with how it works, and second, I like the name :) (for the non-German speaking world, &amp;ldquo;Herbstluft&amp;rdquo; means &amp;ldquo;autumn air&amp;rdquo;, which I think is just beautiful. Once I figure out how to post audio on here, I&amp;rsquo;ll put a file online with the correct pronounciation ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
