<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on 82MHz</title>
    <link>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on 82MHz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://82mhz.net/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Entitled people</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/entitled-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/entitled-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know what to title this post, and I think the title doesn&amp;rsquo;t really capture what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to say, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of anything better either, so please bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago Marques Brownlee (MKBHD) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TitZV6k8zfA&#34;&gt;posted a not very flattering review&lt;/a&gt; of an AI controlled gadget on Youtube which apparently created a controversy online where several people accused him of bankrupting the company by giving their product a negative review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s complete and utter bullshit of course, and he p&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QztFpzKsdeA&#34;&gt;osted a response video&lt;/a&gt; where he defended his review and also stated the more than obvious fact &amp;ldquo;bad reviews don&amp;rsquo;t kill companies, bad products kill companies&amp;rdquo;. Duh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reminded me of a post on Mastodon from Youtuber &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@NotJustBikes&#34;&gt;Not Just Bikes&lt;/a&gt; from a few weeks ago, where he mentioned that he released a video about a bridge in Amsterdam and &lt;a href=&#34;https://social.notjustbikes.com/@notjustbikes/112180659251756070&#34;&gt;people demanded that he take the video down&lt;/a&gt; because it was &amp;ldquo;inappropriate&amp;rdquo; since a few days prior a bridge in Baltimore had collapsed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I can&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder, what the hell is going on in these peoples minds? A tech reviewer isn&amp;rsquo;t allowed to state that a product is bad anymore? Somewhere a bridge collapses and now the entire world isn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to talk about bridges anymore because it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;inappropriate&amp;rdquo;? What&amp;rsquo;s going on here? What kind of world do these people want to live in?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhysicsGirl and Long COVID</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/physicsgirl-and-long-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/physicsgirl-and-long-covid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I found out by chance that Youtuber Dianna Cowern aka PhysicsGirl is suffering from the most severe case of Long COVID&amp;hellip; she&amp;rsquo;s bedridden 24/7 and incapable of doing even the most basic things like reading or even just having a conversation as that immediately worsens her symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s many more like her, millions probably, who are suffering from Long COVID or ME/CFS and who are pretty much forgotten by society because the disease renders them all but invisible to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet they&amp;rsquo;re still there, and they&amp;rsquo;re quietly suffering at home. The acute pandemic may be over, but the long term consequences that some of the afflicted are suffering are still very real and substantial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the positive side, scientists are working hard at figuring out the cause of the illness and are working on potential treatments, and slowly but steadily progress is being made. So there is hope that these people may some day, hopefully soon, be able to live their lives again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer time</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/summer-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/summer-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not time for summer, but switching the clock from winter time to summer time, or daylight saving time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had this switch yesterday, and I hate this time shift with a passion. It&amp;rsquo;s just so unneccessary. And apparently completely impossible now to get rid of, even though it was totally possible to introduce it 45 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this year I noticed something&amp;hellip; I seem to live my life by the clock. And not my internal clock, the external one. I get up when it&amp;rsquo;s time to get up, I have lunch when it&amp;rsquo;s lunchtime, I go to bed when it&amp;rsquo;s bedtime. And for all these things I use the actual time as a reference, and not my internal clock or how I&amp;rsquo;m actually feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was kind of aware of this, but not really, but this year I really noticed it. Having a consistent daily rhythm is a good thing I think, at least for me, but being a slave to the clock definitely is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is something to be more aware of&amp;hellip; how am I feeling, am I actually ready to get up, or tired, or hungry, or do I just do something because it&amp;rsquo;s time for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixed RSS feeds</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/fixed-rss-feeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/fixed-rss-feeds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://0xdstn.site/&#34;&gt;Dustin&lt;/a&gt; notified me that my thoughts posts also showed up in the RSS feed for the posts posts (okay, I need better names for this), so I had a look and fixed it.
So now this should only show up once in your feed reader if you are subscribed to both my feeds. Thanks Dustin!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antisocial Behaviour</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/antisocial-behaviour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/antisocial-behaviour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in a café right now, just watching the people around me&amp;hellip; and three tables from me is a guy constantly on his phone, the other side on speakerphone at full volume, &amp;ldquo;entertaining&amp;rdquo; the entire place with his private conversations. Now he&amp;rsquo;s talking in a foreign language I don&amp;rsquo;t understand, but it&amp;rsquo;s distracting  and annoying nevertheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I look outside the window at a busy street, and another guy just casually parks his car in the second lane (in the middle of the street in other words), gets out and calmly walks away. A minute later an entire bus full of people has to stop behind this car and wait until it can pass by, making everybody on the bus late because one person can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to find a suitable parking spot and walk a few meters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s little behaviours like these that the people doing them don&amp;rsquo;t think twice about, but that make life for other people just a little more unpleasant or annoying. And I&amp;rsquo;m taking it as a reminder for myself to consider the impact of my behaviour on other people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Sabbath finally re-releases the Tony Martin era Albums</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/black-sabbath-finally-re-releases-the-tony-martin-era-albums/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/black-sabbath-finally-re-releases-the-tony-martin-era-albums/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people are at least somewhat familiar with Black Sabbath because of the popularity of Ozzy Osbourne, but fewer people know that they had a decades long career with about a million lineup changes and a lot of different singers in the 80s and 90s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most famous one is of course Ronnie James Dio, but one singer hardly anyone is familiar with is Tony Martin, who recorded a few albums with Sabbath in the late 80s/early 90s, which are in my opinion incredibly overlooked and underrated. The albums were The Eternal Idol, Headless Cross, Tyr, Cross Purposes and Forbidden, and especially Headless Cross and Tyr are two of my favourite Sabbath albums, if not some my favourite metal albums of all time, period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They haven&amp;rsquo;t been available on Spotify or on CD for a long time, but now finally they&amp;rsquo;re being reissued in form of a remastered box set, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be happier to finally see these albums being given the respect and love they deserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a Sabbath fan, but don&amp;rsquo;t know this era of the band, I highly recommend checking it out. It&amp;rsquo;s completely different from the Ozzy material, more similar to the Ronnie James Dio albums with a heavy 80s touch (with lots and lots of reverb!), which means great epic songs and simply fantastic vocals. I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend these albums enough, I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll give them a listen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blabbermouth.net/news/black-sabbath-box-set-of-tony-martin-era-recordings-anno-domini-1989-1995-to-arrive-in-may&#34;&gt;https://blabbermouth.net/news/black-sabbath-box-set-of-tony-martin-era-recordings-anno-domini-1989-1995-to-arrive-in-may&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Context for Links</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/more-context-for-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/more-context-for-links/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by a post by &lt;a href=&#34;https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/giving-context-to-a-blogroll/&#34;&gt;Simone on his Minutes to Midnight blog&lt;/a&gt;, which to my horror I discovered is already three months old (it felt more like three weeks to me), I decided to add a few words of description to the blogs I have linked on my links page. It&amp;rsquo;s a work in progress, and I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely happy yet with all the descriptions I wrote, but it&amp;rsquo;s a start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different RSS feeds for Posts and Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/different-rss-feeds-for-posts-and-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/different-rss-feeds-for-posts-and-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought about whether I should have one RSS feed for everything on the site or separate feeds for posts (longer articles) and thoughts (shorter ones). After getting some feedback and also thinking about it for a bit, I decided to have separate RSS feeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now there&amp;rsquo;s two feeds for the site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://82mhz.net/index.xml&#34;&gt;https://82mhz.net/index.xml&lt;/a&gt; for longer posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://82mhz.net/thoughts/index.xml&#34;&gt;https://82mhz.net/thoughts/index.xml&lt;/a&gt; for shorter thoughts and notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Mode</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/dark-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/dark-mode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I implemented a (pretty rudimentary) dark mode for the website. It&amp;rsquo;s set to follow the operating system preferences for light or dark mode. I considered adding a switch to the website to toggle between light and dark, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is really necessary&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback is of course welcome, as well as bug reports if something isn&amp;rsquo;t working right.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
