<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on 82MHz</title>
    <link>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on 82MHz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://82mhz.net/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Black Sabbath finally re-releases the Tony Martin era Albums</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/black-sabbath-finally-re-releases-the-tony-martin-era-albums/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/black-sabbath-finally-re-releases-the-tony-martin-era-albums/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people are at least somewhat familiar with Black Sabbath because of the popularity of Ozzy Osbourne, but fewer people know that they had a decades long career with about a million lineup changes and a lot of different singers in the 80s and 90s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most famous one is of course Ronnie James Dio, but one singer hardly anyone is familiar with is Tony Martin, who recorded a few albums with Sabbath in the late 80s/early 90s, which are in my opinion incredibly overlooked and underrated. The albums were The Eternal Idol, Headless Cross, Tyr, Cross Purposes and Forbidden, and especially Headless Cross and Tyr are two of my favourite Sabbath albums, if not some my favourite metal albums of all time, period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They haven&amp;rsquo;t been available on Spotify or on CD for a long time, but now finally they&amp;rsquo;re being reissued in form of a remastered box set, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be happier to finally see these albums being given the respect and love they deserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a Sabbath fan, but don&amp;rsquo;t know this era of the band, I highly recommend checking it out. It&amp;rsquo;s completely different from the Ozzy material, more similar to the Ronnie James Dio albums with a heavy 80s touch (with lots and lots of reverb!), which means great epic songs and simply fantastic vocals. I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend these albums enough, I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll give them a listen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blabbermouth.net/news/black-sabbath-box-set-of-tony-martin-era-recordings-anno-domini-1989-1995-to-arrive-in-may&#34;&gt;https://blabbermouth.net/news/black-sabbath-box-set-of-tony-martin-era-recordings-anno-domini-1989-1995-to-arrive-in-may&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Context for Links</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/more-context-for-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/more-context-for-links/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by a post by &lt;a href=&#34;https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/giving-context-to-a-blogroll/&#34;&gt;Simone on his Minutes to Midnight blog&lt;/a&gt;, which to my horror I discovered is already three months old (it felt more like three weeks to me), I decided to add a few words of description to the blogs I have linked on my links page. It&amp;rsquo;s a work in progress, and I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely happy yet with all the descriptions I wrote, but it&amp;rsquo;s a start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different RSS feeds for Posts and Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/different-rss-feeds-for-posts-and-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/different-rss-feeds-for-posts-and-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought about whether I should have one RSS feed for everything on the site or separate feeds for posts (longer articles) and thoughts (shorter ones). After getting some feedback and also thinking about it for a bit, I decided to have separate RSS feeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now there&amp;rsquo;s two feeds for the site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://82mhz.net/index.xml&#34;&gt;https://82mhz.net/index.xml&lt;/a&gt; for longer posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://82mhz.net/thoughts/index.xml&#34;&gt;https://82mhz.net/thoughts/index.xml&lt;/a&gt; for shorter thoughts and notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Mode</title>
      <link>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/dark-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://82mhz.net/thoughts/dark-mode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I implemented a (pretty rudimentary) dark mode for the website. It&amp;rsquo;s set to follow the operating system preferences for light or dark mode. I considered adding a switch to the website to toggle between light and dark, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is really necessary&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback is of course welcome, as well as bug reports if something isn&amp;rsquo;t working right.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
